[Music]
Hey, hey, hey.
Hey,
[Music]
hey, hey.
Heat. Heat. N.
[Music]
Welcome Living Mana Church family. We're
so happy to that you are here with us
today.
Please put in the chat where you are
viewing from. If this is your very first
time, please put a one in the chat. So,
um, our membership will say a special
welcome to you and we will just know
that this is your very first time here
and we are just so happy that you are
here. And if this is not your first
time, please put in the chat where you
are viewing from. We just love to see
where all of you are viewing from. And
again, our membership is going to say
welcome and happy Sabbath to you. So,
it's so good to have all of you here
with us today.
>> Yes, we want to welcome you. We are uh
going to have a very good Sabbath school
today. We're going to be talking about
>> we're going to be continuing our study
on the Christian art of war. Right.
>> I know that uh many of you have been
asking about the book where you can get
it from and unfortunately the book is
not in print
>> right now. Um but we are uploading
chapter by chapter uh so that uh you
know everyone that wants to participate
>> and um go through each chapter with us
uh we'll be able to do that. We upload
those on mighty networks. So um
>> so please download Mighty Networks that
should be coming in the chat right now
so that you can if you don't have Mighty
Networks you can download it by clicking
on the link that's in the chat so that
you can have access to each chapter
which we've already released three
chapters. Actually by uh this morning
you should have four because we're
finishing chapter three and we're going
into chapter four. So please um get on
Mighty Networks if you're not on Mighty
Networks. you definitely uh need to be
uh on Mighty Networks. That's the Living
Mana Church home, our virtual home. And
you've all the amazing things that we do
here at Living Mana Church are on Mighty
Network. So, you definitely want that.
>> Yeah. And uh we we actually moving
through these chapters slower than we
expected because there is so much there.
>> So much. Um, so you know, we are moving
at a pace where if you've missed, you
are going to be able to catch up.
>> Yes.
>> So, make sure you get on my networks
and, uh, like I said, today we're going
to be finishing up chapter 3 and
possibly going into chapter 4.
>> Yes. We'll see how we'll see how it
goes. We have our guest and so we're
excited to bring them on. But before we
bring them on, you have to do the
t-shirt message
>> which is faith
forwarding all issues to heaven.
>> Yes. Forwarding all issues to heaven.
That's what faith is. It's not trying to
in our human nature deal with things. Um
not just holding on to something and
just feeling the anxiety and worry and
despair. That's not faith. Faith is like
something happens and you immediately
just send it right to heaven. Send it to
the throne of grace and God will deal
with it. You know, we experience as, you
know, as a mental health professional, I
hear about anxiety probably every day.
So, in our human nature here on this
earth, we want to deal with things
ourselves. Well, the way we deal with it
is we want to worry about it. We want to
feel the the nervousness and the
despair. But we don't have to do that.
We as Christians know that we can
immediately just take the issue, take
the problem and send it right to God and
he will deal with it for us. So we don't
have to hold on to it. We don't have to
worry and our worry does nothing
anyways. The Bible tells us that. But we
always need that reminder because every
day we are all tempted to just hold on
to it and not forward the problem right
to heaven immediately.
>> And sometimes we struggle doing that.
Yes, we struggle doing it sometimes. We
Yeah, we're all tempted to just hold on
to it.
>> Yeah.
>> So, we need to practice forwarding it to
to to heaven right away.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> All right. So, I think we are going to
Wait, do we have any announcements
before we get into
>> um I Well, right before in the divine
worship service, I'll have um
announcements, but uh right now, no, we
can save them all for then. So, you have
to stay tuned for announcements.
>> So, we're going to go ahead and pray and
then we're going to invite our guests
on.
>> Yes.
>> Uh we're going to continue on. So, we've
had the same group of guests.
>> Yes. It's been wonderful.
>> We've been switching out one and two
here and there, some that haven't been
able to make it.
>> Today, we have four.
>> Yeah. So,
>> we're excited for the four.
>> Yeah. So, let's pray and uh we'll invite
our guests on and then we're going to
continue our study. We're going to pick
up in chapter three,
>> the end of chapter 3.
>> The end of chapter 3, uh where we left
off last week.
>> Yes.
>> So, let's pray. Heavenly Father,
>> we ask Lord that as uh as we open this
study, as we conclude our study on
chapter 3 of the Christian Art of War,
um David's Mighty Men. Lord, may we
continue to learn lessons. May we
continue to learn how to fight this this
fight of faith. And um Lord, guide our
thoughts. God our words, God our guests,
and uh may everything that is said be
glorifying and uplifting to you. To you
in Jesus name we pray. Amen.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> All right.
>> So uh as we're bringing our guests on.
>> Yes.
>> Um I think we're actually Did I just say
we're picking up with Men of Night? I
didn't say what we're picking up.
>> I don't think you said I don't think.
No, I don't. No. Not since we've been
live.
>> Yeah.
>> Not since we've been live. So all right
we
are are our everyone you guys are all
familiar you've seen our the our guest
are not strangers to you. So we have
brother Terry there on the top uh corner
and sister Bri keys uh right across from
him and then we have Melinda. Welcome
welcome and brother Kashif. So good to
see all four of you. We are so excited
to what God is going to give you to
share with all of us um as we all just
talk and dialogue and and talk together.
And those um that are viewing with us,
please um if you have um are on Mighty
Networks and you have you have access to
get the uh chapter 3 or if you already
have it, please go along with us and
please put in the chat uh what you're
the what you're getting out of the study
as well because this is Sabbath school.
We want to hear from you. This is an
interactive Sabbath school where we're
sharing and you're sharing and we want
to hear from you. So, we look forward to
to what God um is giving all of us today
in this in this final part of chapter 3.
>> Amen. So, um let's recap.
>> And I think what I'd like to do is uh
the last thing we talked about was um uh
keeping rank. keeping Rake
>> and we were talking about the importance
of um
you know understanding that our fight
>> is we're not just fighting for ourselves
but we're fighting to be an example for
other people as well.
>> Right?
>> So our example you know if you're in a
battle and you see people
>> falling in battle
>> that's going to be a discouraging thing.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. And I think every time the enemy
can get somebody to fall in battle
>> that as others look on it's it's a
discouraging thing.
>> You know that's you know if people leave
the church if people turn their backs on
God
>> right
>> you might be like how how could that
person that person was so strong that
person was so this. So we have to
understand that you know part of our
battle is to keep the morale
high
in the army right keep the morale high
among our fellow soldiers
>> and so we have a double responsibility
of not just taking care of ourselves
>> but being our brother's keepers. Mhm.
>> So, um, let's let's just cap just talk a
little bit about more a little bit more
about that before we move on to the to
the next segment of chapter 3.
>> And if anyone wants to jump in and just
kind of build on that, let let's do
that.
>> I just want to say that we've talked a
lot about the individual battle in the
Christian art of war, but what you're
talking about, what you're mentioning
now is, you know, um, the Christian art
of war. Yes, it's an individual battle,
but it's also there are others on the
field with us and we're all fighting the
same enemy and we're should be working
together. And if we break ranks, then
that's going to make us weaker.
>> And so, and then the and the and the
enemy just can come in there and do what
he wants.
>> Yeah.
>> Like,
>> you're not just fighting
>> Yeah.
>> for yourself.
>> We're not just fighting for ourselves.
>> Yeah. Um All right. Anybody want to jump
in and and and build on that thought?
All right.
Don't be shy.
Oh, well, I think Bri was started,
Terry. I think so. I I heard her. I
Yeah. Yeah. And then you can follow up
after her, though. Go ahead, Bri.
Um, I was just going to say it that
reminds me of a a quote we have up um at
the elementary school I work at. Um, and
it says, "Be the example um that you
wish to see."
>> Um, and I keep that with me every day. I
know the the quote is put up there for
the kids, but I think it's a a really
good quote for staff as well. Um,
>> I keep that in mind when I'm getting
dressed in the morning. um and what I
say to the to the kids, how I say it, uh
my interactions with other staff um
and especially around
non-eventous families who are present at
the school. Um,
again, just being making sure that
um
my character and my actions
reflect God's character. Uh, so that I'm
not causing someone else to stumble or
someone else to say, "Oh, well, you
know, like look at those Adventists. um
they
come off so righteous but here she is
behaving contrary to how you know Christ
would
want her to behave. So I think like
pastor said it's really important that
um we're mindful because we're not only
fighting for ourselves we're fighting
for those around us too. God called us
to um share the gospel with others
um and to kind of plant the seed for
others. And we can't do that if we're
causing other people to stumble,
>> right? Yes. Yeah.
>> Amen.
>> Great example. You were going to say you
had something to share, Terry.
>> Yeah. Um, you know, I'm really thankful
uh that the Lord gave pastor uh this
particular topic of keeping rank and
seeing ourselves as a part of the
overall family of God. I mean I I I we
all know that living mana is a global
community, a virtual community, but we
get the opportunity to experience
different uh languages, different
cultures, different ethnicities, and
that's the beautiful thing about the
kingdom of God. But here in the west,
um, those of us who live in the west
know that we live in somewhat, not
somewhat really an individualistic
culture. And the Christian culture is
communal. It's family. Uh, uh, as the
living man of prayer ministry leader,
the first word that God teaches me about
prayer is our, our, father.
>> And so, right off the bat, he's telling
me, Terry, you need to start thinking
about family. uh the Hebrews call it
mishpaha. And so I'm to think that way.
And so that's going to take some
practice and some transformation in my
thought when everything around me every
day, everywhere, all the time is about
me me.
>> So I'm I'm really thankful for this
section.
>> Yeah. Yeah. There's a verse in John
17:19 where Jesus is speaking and he
says uh for their sake I sanctify myself
that they also might be sanctified
through the truth.
>> So Jesus literally says I'm sanctifying
myself for their sake.
I think that's a powerful
illustration of Jesus himself saying,
"I'm living this way as an example to
others."
So his battle was not for himself, it
was for our sakes. And so we have to
kind of approach our battle the same
way,
>> right? But I'm sanctifying myself for
um
you know my family, for the neighbors,
for
my enemies, for my friends.
>> Your sanctification
does not only have an impact on you, but
it has an impact on others. And uh when
we understand that principle, I am my
brother's keeper. that's going to I
think have a profound impact on this
idea of keeping rank.
>> And I think our journey is easier when
we keep rank if that makes sense because
we're
>> we're all of our energy is going to the
enemy and not fighting each other. But
the enemy causes us or tries to cause us
to break rank and then he's able to make
us weaker and it's harder and he knows
that
>> because if we're together we're
stronger.
>> So that means that the enemy is pretty
much
one of the things I think he does is how
can I get you to break rank?
>> He just
>> how can I get you to not be on the same
page? How can I get you to not be
moving?
>> Yeah,
>> because think about it. Keep rank. If
you're a soldier
on the battlefield, you all need to be
moving at the same pa same pace,
>> same direction. And
I think if we're if we're moving at
different speeds, if we're
if we're not
moving
in uh if we're not moving in
sync,
>> if we're not moving thinking about Okay,
because you could, you know, I might be
super fast and you might be slow.
>> If I'm super fast,
I might want to slow down to keep rank
with you.
>> Amen.
>> Right? And I don't mean slow down in a
sense of well, oh, let me s I'm saying
like if the object is for us to move
together.
>> I want to move
in unison
with my slowest person. I want to move
in unison so that the so that the army
stays together. You don't want to lose
>> because once you scatter
>> once you scatter
um
that's how the devil
>> that's how the devil wins. There was a
video Terry I don't know if you remember
this um this was back at Campbell
when at the beginning of the video. Do
you remember?
>> He said yes right away. So he must
remember
>> in the video
>> he's talking about that lion.
>> The lion. Oh,
>> and the uh the deer.
>> Yeah, I remember.
>> And it was two deer. Was it Was it deer?
>> Yeah,
>> it was two deer fighting.
>> Mhm.
>> And the lion was just like,
>> "Was it deer though?" Okay, it doesn't
matter.
>> And whatever it was,
>> they didn't even notice that he was
coming.
>> They didn't notice he was coming. They
were busy, busy,
>> locked in battle
>> and they didn't mercy.
>> And the line was just like, I cannot
believe that this happened. play that
video at the beginning of every church
service of every church,
>> not just Adventist church in America.
>> It's like this is what y'all don't want
to do.
>> Yeah,
>> that's right.
>> Because the enemy, Satan just sends like
his demons out and parks them. I I mean,
of course, he they're everywhere dealing
with all kinds of things, but he
definitely sends them to churches and
he's like, "Okay, this is the chaos
we're going to start here." And if it's
not just between
individuals, they start arguing about
theology and all just different
different type of stuff. There's just
always arguments going all the time.
>> And that's that's just what he does.
>> Amen.
>> A house divided against itself cannot
stand.
>> Indeed.
>> Amen.
>> And then I'm using churches. I don't
know why I'm so focused on churches, but
he does the same things in our marriages
and in homes and just does all, you
know, he's just always trying to cause
>> division.
>> Yeah. any type of relation. And that's
why I love um
um Philippians 2:3, you know, let
nothing be done through strife or vain
glory, but in loneliness of mind, let
each esteem other better than
themselves.
>> So,
>> amen.
>> You got no time to
think about fighting if you're thinking
about the best interest for your brother
or sister.
>> Yeah.
you know, um, another thing I really
appreciate about living mana in mental
health Mondays and, uh, the things that
that sister, you were teaching with with
Dr. Christina, I love, uh, dealing with
chronic trauma.
>> Trauma. Yeah.
>> Um, because, yeah, because personally, I
know that one of the ways the enemy got
me isolated and caused me to break rank
uh, was through shame, isolation, and
guilt. And a lot of that came from my
own personal traumas. So I know that
even if I'm a person who's not fighting
with other believers, I may be that
person who's so isolated because I think
no one understands what I'm going
through or even shame. No one can will
ever understand this struggle when the
Bible says resist the devil knowing that
your brothers throughout the whole world
are going through the same things you're
going through. And so one of the ways he
gets us isolated, I know he had me
isolated this way for a long time, uh
was just, you know, not trusting people
and believing the lie that people
closest to you hurt you. And so
everybody was kept at arms distance. And
um I love what I saw God do in small
groups, small men's groups when men
begin to share their struggles and hear
their struggles coming out of the mouth
of another. And so the Bible does tell
us confess your faults one to another.
Pray for one another. So God has so
beautifully put this thing together
where we can be a supportive, nurturing,
loving, growing together unit.
>> Yeah.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> Amen. I was thinking that that concept
of breaking rank, of not breaking rank
is so important to God that he even
gives a parable about it in the 99
sheep.
>> And and the one that broke rank,
>> but he didn't leave him,
>> right?
>> Yeah.
>> He broke rank. And it was so important
>> that the shepherd is like, I got to go
find this one sheep. Yeah.
>> Who's broken rank?
>> Wow.
Praise God.
>> So, um, what a what a lesson
when,
>> you know, think about how many members
of the church, they break rank,
>> not intentionally,
>> right? But they might break rank through
discouragement,
>> right?
>> They might break rank through
so many different reasons.
And does the army,
you know, there's a popular song, I will
send out an army to find you.
>> That is today.
>> Amen.
>> So
>> I rescue.
>> Yeah. I will rescue you. Right. That
idea of understanding that man, even
when rank is broken,
>> okay, we're not leaving a soldier
behind.
>> Amen.
>> You just think of Desmond Doss.
>> Desmond Doss.
>> Yes,
>> indeed.
>> Yeah,
>> Desmond Doss. I mean, what a
>> powerful analogy of one more Lord.
>> One more.
>> Yeah.
>> So, okay. So, anyone want to add
anything to that to the idea of breaking
rank?
>> Okay.
>> All right.
>> We juiced we juiced it enough.
>> We we juiced it. So let's uh let let's
move to this next section. Um which uh
and I think we talked about this too.
Did we talk about not of double heart
last week guys or did we just kind of
barely scratch it or what?
>> I don't think we I don't that doesn't I
don't think we did.
>> Okay. So let me read this next paragraph
and and if it rings a bell then we can
talk a little about a little bit about
it. So let's
>> uh this next paragraph says uh talks
about not of double heart and it says
they were not double-minded they were
single in per they were singular in
purpose they were not fickle God's
warriors God needs warriors who with an
eye single to the glory of God will not
turn back when things get hard when the
numbers seem stacked against us when the
numbers seem stacked against us against
us when temptations seem to attack our
heart parcel on every side we do not
turn and run but stand in the midst of
it to deliver it from the hand of the
enemy by the grace of the power of God.
So this analogy comes from the story of
one of David's mighty men who is
standing in the middle of a parcel to
deliver it from the Philistines
and everybody is running away and this
one guy stands his ground.
>> A double-minded man is unstable in all
his ways.
God is looking for warriors who are
willing to stand their ground no matter
how overwhelming
>> the obstacles are before them.
So what do you what do you guys think
about the idea of not being you know not
of double heart? So remember this whole
chapter is talking about the mighty it's
describing David's mighty men.
Um, and we're looking at all the
descriptions and bringing spiritual
application to those descriptions.
>> So, why do you think it's important not
to be doubleminded
in conflict?
I think it weakens you for battle to be
double-minded.
>> Um, you're not going to be well, you're
not going to be as sharp. You're going
to lose. You're If you're double-minded,
you're going to lose to your enemy. So,
you're already going to lose right off
the bat.
>> Yeah.
>> You've already lost basically.
>> So, the way you just said,
>> um,
>> go ahead. Go ahead.
>> Oh, yeah. And yeah, it could it could
take us right back to the previous thing
of, you know, breaking rank. If you're
if you're doubleminded and it's and it's
visible for others to see,
>> then um you could cause other people to,
you know, get discouraged and and very
rank because they especially if
for the lack of not looking at it from a
prideful way, especially if people look
up to you in a certain light, you know,
they always see that you've been strong
in the Lord and you you've always been
able to give good counsel according to
the word of God.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> And if they see you um you know having
a double a double way of whatever
situation then um you know you could
cause people to break rank.
>> Yeah.
>> So it just goes to show how everything
just goes hand in hand.
And I think we become double-minded when
we because the enemy gives us the spirit
of fear and that causes us to
to step back or try to do something
different or or try to play both sides
of the field, if you will, or whatever.
Um, and so we can't allow fear to lead
us or or to rule us even when we're in
battle. We have to feel like we have to
trust God. Kind of like we were talking
about last week. Um God is basically
doing like
>> go
>> yeah he's just yeah basically just hand
it's his strength um it may be yeah it's
his strength and we can depend upon him
to be able to beat the enemy
>> and when we're in battle we can't move
in fear or we're going to slip and do
something we're not supposed to do.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So if I have uh two
glasses of water
or two glasses and one of those and I
have a you know water in one glass let's
say that that water in one glass I'm I'm
that glass is 100%.
>> It's full.
>> There's no uh you know there's no it's
100%. and think of that as strength, as
energy. But if I'm double glassed,
right? If I have one glass here and one
glass here, and I'm pouring some of that
water from the main glass that has 100%
water into that other glass. Now, I'm
not as efficient in either.
>> Right.
>> So, there's some water here and there's
some water here. So if we think of the
double-minded man
>> as hey if you're single if you're
single-minded all your energy is
dedicated to God.
>> But if you're doubleminded then that
energy is already split.
>> And whether it's 7520 or 7525 or 50/50
whatever it's going to make you weaker
automatically.
>> Right.
>> So
>> I have a question.
>> Go ahead. Go ahead. Melinda.
Is being doubleminded the same as being
lukewarm?
>> That's where I was getting ready to head
to.
>> I would I would say so.
>> I would say half hot, half cold.
>> Yeah.
>> One glass is hot, the other is cold.
And still fear is the even for
lukewarmness, fear of of surrendering
all to God or letting him lead the way
completely and giving you strength is
still the motivation. It's still what's
causing you to do that like Peter like
he he could walk on water when he was
just trusting Jesus and but as soon as
he stopped Yeah. and got afraid that's
when he he fell.
>> So what we will fall and lose when we're
having when we allow fear to take over.
>> Yeah.
You can't fight a war with divided
commitment. You can't fight for two
armies at once.
>> Yeah.
>> So, you got to pick a you got to pick a
team.
>> Yeah.
>> And man, the last person
>> No man can serve two masters.
>> Yeah.
>> Man,
>> the last person you want to be on a
battlefield with is someone who is
>> unstable,
>> right? someone who's doublehearted,
someone who is like, "Oh, well,
>> because you want to you want to look
over and see
>> confidence in the face of your fellow
soldiers, right?
>> You don't want to see fear. You don't
want to you don't want to see any of
that because, you know, you need all the
confidence you can muster
in yourself and look over and see
someone that's, you know, double-minded,
unstable, that can be discouraging.
Mhm.
Amen.
>> When you stop looking at Jesus and
looking at other people and at yourself,
that's when you're going to get wobbly.
Just keep looking at Jesus for your
strength.
>> Yeah.
>> To be able to fight the battle.
>> Yeah. So, Peter was stable on the water.
>> He was stable on the water.
>> Kind of crazy.
>> Which is very crazy.
>> But as soon as he took his eyes off of
Jesus, he became unstable and began to
sink.
>> That's what happens.
>> Yeah. So they were they were confident.
Go ahead.
>> Yeah. Last last Sabbath, Melinda said
something that I just can't get away
from. It's it stuck in my mind. And she
looked at David's rock or David's stone
that he flung at Goliath and she said,
"Jesus is the rock."
>> And even in the afterlow, a lot of
people was were saying, "You know what?
We got a rock for everything we face,
for every giant in our life. And people
really grasp the whole of that. And I
did. And and that's been on my heart.
And the Lord has really inspired me with
a thought that started with what Melinda
said. Um I can't throw the rock of Jesus
at my problems if I'm double-minded and
and I'm double-hearted.
>> Yeah.
>> And so I was looking I went back into
the book and I looked again at the
mighty man. And with the exception of
Adoni,
Elheiser, Shama, the three men who went
and got the water for David
>> and even David himself when he faced
Goliath, they were all Philistines. And
he he was specific when he made
reference to me. He says uncircumcised
Philistines.
>> Yeah.
>> So if I'm not truly circumcised in my
heart,
>> I can only go back and forth. I will
throw Jesus while I'm sitting in front
of this camera. But when I'm alone and
nobody else is watching, what stone am I
throwing then?
>> Uh if I'm not truly had an encounter
with God where he I've really had the
true circumcision of heart where I've
put off the old man and put on the new,
then I'm going to be back and forth
because I when I'm when I'm when
everybody's looking and I got to do
what's right and say what's right. Yeah,
I'm going to put on that act. But but
there's a double-mindedness going on,
doubleheartedness going on. And so I've
got to have that true genuine encounter
with the Lord where he transforms me and
all I got is Jesus, you know, in my
back.
>> So, u
make a little warrior for sharing that.
>> Amen.
>> Amen. Maybe were you saying
>> I was saying that kind of takes me back
up to earlier in chapter three um the
the beginning of chapter 3 where he was
saying that um how the mighty men kind
of came to be um
the story kind of described them being
small children and you know coming in
hearing the story of um this little boy
who's no older than them um and he slays
Goliath right and he has this um this
incredible faith that encouraged them to
have incredible faith. So much faith
that they grew up um and helped David
become king um
>> and become these men of valor. And it's
kind of the same for us. Um we can't
encourage others to to be men and women
women of valor if we're double-minded.
>> Yeah.
>> Amen.
>> That's right.
>> Amen. That's right. Melinda, I think I
heard you trying to chime in there, too,
when Bri was starting. Did you have
something?
>> I wanted to um go back on something that
Brother Terry said where he was talking
about um circumcision of heart and
stuff. So, last week um in my personal
worship, I realized that we actually
have two rocks that we can choose to
fight with.
>> One is Jesus, the rock,
>> and then the other is our stony heart.
Wow.
>> And sometimes the reason why we fall on
the battlefield is because we're
fighting with the wrong rock.
>> God's like, "No, no, no, no. I need to
turn that into flesh so that you realize
that no, that's not the rock you're
supposed to be fighting with.
>> You got to h like this is not how it
works."
And how often we as double-minded people
pull out the wrong rock and then fail.
Yeah.
>> Hallelujah.
>> Melinda.
>> Yeah.
>> I don't know. I don't know who sent you.
>> Amen.
>> I'm just saying,
>> you know, Melinda be bringing that fire,
pastor.
>> Yes. Every week, we love it.
>> She just
>> Yeah, she just touched on that
aidextrous thing I was getting ready to
talk about last week.
>> You know what, Melinda? You're going to
have to preach that before he preaches
it so
he doesn't steal your steal your stuff.
>> What were you saying? Sorry, Terry.
>> That ties in with with what you were
gonna what you were going to share last
week.
>> Yeah. Be Yeah. Because one of the
characteristics you pulled out about the
mighty men is they were ambidextrous,
right? They were ambidextrous. They
could throw with the right a sling a
stone with the right hand or with the
left hand. And
>> the way she just laid that thing out by
the grace of God is that, you know, the
enemy wants to change the way we're
fighting.
>> It doesn't matter which hand we're
using. We ought to be using Jesus. We
ought to be showing Jesus to the world.
But the enemy says, "No, here's what I'm
gonna have you do. With this hand, I'm
gonna have you put on that Jesus look.
You put on your religious face. And then
with this hand, you going to throw that
that flesh out there. You know, that
hearty heart, that hard heart." So, wow.
>> Beautiful parallel there. she brought
out.
>> Yeah. And that's powerful for us to be
fighting with the wrong stone
>> because really the right stone when
you're throwing a stone
at your especially if it's a person.
>> The Bible tells us
that the stones we're supposed to be
throwing at our enemies are hot coals.
>> Yes.
[Music]
>> Wow.
>> Love stones.
love stones. Take that
>> and that take that is
do good unto them that you know what I'm
saying
>> do good unto those are the stones that
God has sent out I need you to fight
with these stones
>> I need you to fight with this stone
>> the stone of love
>> you're heaping hot coals of fire
>> and those coals of fire are meant to
convert they're not meant to destroy
>> so um you know powerful thought of the
kind of weapons
you know this kind this weapon of the
stone and fighting with the wrong stone
>> the carnal mind the carnal heart
um very powerful thought
>> yes
>> I don't know if I shared this last week
but uh did we talk about oh oh that I
could get a drink from the well did we
talk about that last week
>> not last week now
>> no
>> is this in chapter three
>> yeah I think it's in chapter three
although I I didn't.
>> Go ahead.
>> The three mighty men went to get it.
>> No, we didn't talk about it, but it's
there.
>> We need to there.
>> It's powerful
>> because that to me is like one of the
most
inspiring
um examples of the w the the wise men,
the mighty men's love for David. Right.
In the story, he's, you know, there's no
indication that he says this to anybody.
The the the story almost gives it like
he's talking to himself and he just says
to himself, "Oh, that I could get a
drink
>> from the well at Bethlehem."
>> And what he was meaning was talking out
loud.
>> Yeah. He's talking out loud and he's
like basically saying
>> that,
>> you know, I cannot wait for this city to
be to be mine, for us to take this city.
>> And the wise men, the Why do I keep
saying the wise men? The three the
mighty men appear to overhear him
because he doesn't send them on this
mission. And the way the way we know he
doesn't send them on this mission is
because
well we'll talk about that in a minute.
>> So they overhear David and they're like,
"Hey, let's go down to the well where
the Philistines are. They're they hold
that territory right now
>> and let's get them a drink of water from
the well.
>> And you know, I dramatize the story. Um
the Philistines are all hanging out
where they're hanging out and they see
in the distance three three guys walking
toward them and they're like, "Who are
they?" Then they see as they get closer
they see that they're Israelites and
they're like, "Oh, we're about to have
some fun. Three of them, all of us." And
they probably send out like six guys to
go take down these three guys. And the
next thing they know, these six guys
drop. And then they're like, "What?"
Then they send out another 10 and them
10 drop.
>> And now they're sending out this, you
know, a horde of people. And these three
guys fight their way. And the confused
Philistines must be like, "What are they
doing?" They fight their way to the
well,
take out a flask, dip the flask into the
well to get water, and then start
fighting their way back out.
>> That is some
>> some love and honor for Yeah.
>> And when they bring it to David, David
is stunned
>> and he's like, "God forbid that I drink
this water." I mean, just the whole
story,
>> I think it's like we we ought to be
asking,
"How much can I do for Jesus?"
>> Right.
>> What else can I do for Jesus?
>> That's going to bring him
>> and I
>> Sorry.
>> Yeah. Go ahead.
>> Yeah. Michaela and I were actually
discussing this story like last week and
we were like really stuck on how
reckless these three um might are and at
some point she just goes like you know
what Melinda
imagine the fear that these Philistines
suddenly have because you've got these
three guys
>> Yeah.
>> and they just like slaughter a whole I
don't know lot of Philistines
>> and then you're thinking about what that
army comes.
>> Yeah.
>> That that's like a powerful testimony to
>> Yes.
>> You know, the strength of the rest of
the army. I mean, just three guys.
>> Yep.
>> Like you were you fight the army. And
she was like that probably tore down a
lot of morale,
>> right? In that,
>> you know.
>> Yeah.
that that uh commitment
to
um to follow Jesus is the kind
>> that is the exact kind of commitment
that we need in the spiritual realm,
right?
>> To follow Jesus.
>> He is thirsting
>> for drink from the well, but not of an
earthly well, but the well of our
hearts. Yeah, he just he's thirsting to
just take over our hearts. That's right.
Us to allow him to do that.
>> So, we need to go get him a drink.
>> Imagine the beauty though if I could we
could have that same kind of love one
for another.
>> Yes.
>> Imagine if we could be that committed to
I'm just going to go down here. Look,
first lady just wants a drink of that
water and I'm about to go down through
here and get that drink of water and
bring it back,
>> you know, or whatever pastor needs or
whatever Bri needs or whatever Kashif
needs or Melinda or whatever my brothers
and sisters need. I'm I'm ready to lay
down my life for them, you know, for
their needs.
>> That that's that's deep.
That's that's pretty
>> especially in a world where everything
seems to be an inconvenience, you know,
>> are you willing to drop everything right
then and there to aid a brother or
sister?
And um
>> greater love.
>> Yeah. That um
>> that is very
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. And I think if that spirit was uh
was in our families and in our
marriages,
>> how much different things would be.
>> But it's like, what? You want water?
Well, you need to go get it yourself,
>> right? But what if what if
>> Yeah.
>> What if we treated our spouses like,
>> "Is this what you want? Is this what you
you need water? I'm going to get it for
you."
>> Right? And all of us have our different
needs. And we're talking, you know,
again, how do we learn how to keep rank
and move at the same pace spiritually?
And when, you know, when someone is is
weak or struggling on a verge of
breaking rank, how do I get that person
that drink of water to keep that person
going?
>> Right?
>> Amen. Whether it's your spouse or your
kids or whoever,
are you willing to break through
the noise and the all those things
>> to get that well to refresh
the soul of Jesus, to refresh the soul
of your neighbor, to refresh the soul of
your spouse, to refresh the soul of your
children. We ought to be willing to
break through
uh any army
to get that drink
>> to satisfy.
>> Amen.
>> All right, let's move on to the to to
men of men of might. I thought we were
gonna like run through this the rest of
this chapter very quickly, but it looks
like that's not going to happen because
where we were supposed where I was
thinking we were going to begin is right
where we're be right where we're getting
to right now. So
1 Corinth I mean 1 Chronicles 12:8.
Uh it says and of the Gadites they
separated themselves unto David into the
hold to the wilderness. And there's a
couple of categories here that we can
talk about. Men of might, that's one.
>> Men of war, that's two. Fit for the
battle, that's three. Could handle
shield and buckler, that's four. Whose
faces were like the faces of lions,
that's five. And who were as swift as
the rose upon the mountains, that's six.
So, there are six areas for us to talk
about. And now I'm pretty sure that we
probably
>> we'll probably get through this and not
get into chap not get into uh chapter
four,
>> right?
>> But um let's talk about men of might
first.
>> Men of might. What what comes to your
mind when you hear men of might? And I
know I think
of
the fact that it is through weakness
that we become strong.
>> Amen.
>> Yes.
>> Right. So it is not our might but the
might of Christ
which requires us
to be weak to know our weakness and to
know God's strength.
So what does this how does weakness
become strength?
Um
so that we can be men of might that's
the question
as we all think.
Well, I know for me personally, it
I had to be broken and
the Lord uh was merciful to me in
allowing me to be broken in the way that
I was. Many many uh who took the same
journey I took of rebellion and and
darkness and pain and just running and
hurting myself and hurting other people.
Many others
completely destroyed and didn't get the
opportunity. But God gave me the
opportunity in my darkest hour at my
lowest point to be able to look at him
and look at his love and look at the
opportunity he was giving me. Uh you
know, but it it took that brokenness and
kind of at the same time while I was
seeing my my circumstances, I was also
seeing God's goodness and God's love and
his hand that was extended to me. And
so, uh, yeah, the Lord allowed me to be
broken in a unique way to realize, okay,
you've run, you've run, you've run,
you've run, and here I am still. You got
a chance. And so, it was his love that
woke me up at my lowest point.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> I think for me, I went
ahead. Sorry. Go ahead. Go ahead.
>> Okay. Breathe in, Melinda. Okay.
I think for me it um it brings to mind
kind of trust and faith. Um in chapter
three it says um these were men of
these were men of these were not men of
uh might or power. These were men of
might or power. This power did not come
from within. It was the power of God uh
>> upon which they depended. They could not
perform such incredible feats without
him. Um, and that
it it kind of brings me to
the reward that he gives them. Like he
rewards them with this incredible
strength and the ability to overcome
um armies of hundreds
um
just on their faith alone. And it brings
me kind of to
surrender
>> kind of saying, "Okay, God, I can't do
this, but you can." Uh, and that's kind
of
>> where the reward comes from. He gives us
this unimaginable strength to persevere
in to kind of overcome any battle,
honestly.
>> Yeah.
>> Amen.
>> Yeah. So, what I was going to say was um
Psalm 24 and that's the I mean to me
it's classic. I just like this song. It
has like nostalgic stuff, you know,
Bible stories and
>> I don't know. But it's the psalm where
it says um lift up your heads, oh ye
gates.
>> Yeah.
>> The king of glory can come in. And then
they go ahead and they ask who is this
king of glory? And then it goes on to
say, this is happening in verse eight.
goes on to say, "The Lord strong and
mighty, the Lord mighty in battle."
>> Amen.
>> And that's what makes
men mighty in battle makes me think of
this verse where it's like Lord mighty
in battle.
>> Yeah.
>> Amen.
>> I agree. it it comes it comes right back
down to surrender
and the moment especially if let's say
you're struggling with with with anger
and um you know that you should
surrender and you should give it to God
that's how you're going to get the
victory.
>> Yeah.
>> And then when you you do that you use
all your might to surrender and then you
see how strong you become in
>> your weakness through God.
>> Yeah.
I think that uh it's kind of like a um
it leads into this next phrase which is
men of war fit for the battle. And I'll
just combine those fit for the battle.
>> Um what comes to mind when you think of
fit for the battle?
Uh and I'll throw this out here and it
might be it might seem offensive at
first but please understand. Um I think
um we can either be spiritually fit or
spiritually fat.
>> What are we
>> right?
to be fit for the battle
um
is going to be different from
uh from failing
all the time.
>> Okay,
>> that works for fat.
>> Failing
>> failing all the time.
>> Okay,
>> soul.
>> Wow. Am I fit?
>> F A T
>> or am I fat?
We're not talking physically. We're
talking spiritually. So
>> don't anybody be like, "Pastor,
>> are we fit for the battle?" And to be
fit for the battle, like,
you know, fitness comes through
exercise.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> And so when the Bible says that we
should exercise godliness,
what does that look like?
That's that's the practice.
>> Amen.
>> Right. I think we were talking about it
last week, the stones. Like, you know,
David was probably in his yard using the
sling quite often, just aiming at stuff.
>> Ah, I hit that. I hit that. I hit that.
So,
>> yeah, that wasn't his first time using
the sling. So, how do we learn how to
practice godliness
>> so that we can or exercise godliness?
>> Because that's how we become fit
spiritually. We have to exercise
godliness.
>> We have to exercise it continually.
>> There's a phrase, if you don't use it,
you lose it.
>> You don't stay fit forever without
continually exercising.
>> Y
>> the your body and your muscles begin to
decline when you're no longer
exercising. And then you become
spiritually fat.
>> Y
>> Amen. Amen.
>> It's true. Amen.
>> So that idea of men of might, men of
war, fit for the battle. They're
exercising
godliness.
And then it goes on to say they could
handle shield and buckler,
>> which you know to me again is
how many weapons can you use? It's kind
of like what it was saying, right?
>> How many weapons are at your disposal?
And when we look at the Christian armor,
uh you know, you got the breastplate of
righteousness, the helmet of salvation,
the sword of the spirit. Um, and later
on in the chapter, we're I mean, not in
the chapter, in the book, we're going to
see that there are many more weapons
>> than just, you know, what people
typically think of the the sword of the
spirit, the, you know, your Lord's good
about with truth.
>> There are a bunch
>> of faith weapons
>> in the Bible.
>> I remember a few weeks ago, we had the
>> the viewing the viewing audience start
putting weapons into the chat. So, Mhm.
>> There are a lot of weapons.
>> Yep.
>> So,
>> and so that idea of handling shield and
buckler again tells me that they were
skilled
>> in all different types of battle.
>> Amen.
Pastor, I like I like with the shield
and because the shield connects us back
to
marching in rank because if I'm thinking
about using the shield typically, you
know, uh the first thing I think about
is, okay, I got to protect myself,
>> but that shield's not just for
protecting me.
>> I've got to learn how to shield others
who are being oppressed and others who
are doing being done wrong. and I've got
to be a voice for those who can't speak
up and those that are marginalized or
those are mistreated or in injustice.
And I love what you were teaching
particularly doing uh COVID, you begin
to bring out a whole lot of stuff about
our movement, the Advent movement really
started off with being a voice for those
who were, you know, oppressed.
>> Yeah.
>> And so I I love the fact that our shield
is not just for us, it's for everyone in
need. And um it kind of, you know, I
know we've we've we've gone past getting
that drink of water, but I I keep
thinking back about the woman at the
well and how she went to get a drink of
water and Jesus knew all these things
that were going on in her life and he
could have easily, you know, put her
down and condemned her for those things,
but but he couldn't because that's not
who he was. But he was more interested
in meeting her needs. And so my prayer
for me and for all of us, Lord, help us
to figure out ways to look to you. Help
us to know how to meet the needs of
people because people are acting the way
they're acting, behaving the way they're
behaving because their needs aren't
being met.
>> Their spiritual needs. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Powerful powerful thoughts. Powerful
thoughts. Um
I know that there are and you know these
two last two points I should say kind of
bring us right back to everything we've
been talking about which is they had
faces like lions
>> and they were swift as roles and uh the
idea of faces like lions you know it it
again points back to courage
>> right um to be swift as roles
upon the mountains
>> it means that where others would fall
they were stable
Right. So, you know, the Bible says,
"Now unto him that is able to keep you
from falling."
>> Like when you see those mountains, you
ever seen those uh uh the mountain
goats?
>> Mountain goats. They're they're on the
very
>> like they're on these cliffs that are so
steep
>> and just like
>> how in the world
>> did are you not falling
>> or not afraid?
>> That's what I was about to say again.
They're not afraid.
>> They're not because they're not afraid.
>> Yeah,
>> they're I but you know I mean even
they're not afraid
>> not being afraid is not going to keep
you from falling off that cliff. So
they're not afraid. They're they're
trust they're trusting whatever skills
they have
>> the skills
>> they're trusting that and so
>> they were agile they're agile
>> very
used to it
>> they're used to it
>> so
>> you know we fall on level ground
>> to be as swift as the rolls upon the
mountain side
>> to me is like where where others easily
fall
You are like a row upon the mountain
side. Like you're not falling.
>> Wow.
>> Right. How do we get to that place where
we're like the rose upon the sides of
the mountains? Go ahead. Somebody was
gonna say something.
>> Okay. Sorry. I don't know if anybody
else was going to say something. Is
anybody else going to say something?
>> No. Go ahead, Melinda.
>> No, go ahead.
>> Yeah. I really don't know. I don't know.
Correct me if I'm wrong. I don't know if
you can take it this far, but I'm really
into Bible prophecy, so like I can't
help myself.
So when I hear this as swift as rosen
mountain side, I immediately think about
how beautiful are the feet of those in
the mountains good news
>> and then I think about how we have this
burning mountain falling into the sea
>> and how it's a symbol for Babylon and
how there's a message going out to
Babylon that says come out of her my
people and it's this message of good
news
>> but you're supposed to proclaim
at the mountain of Babylon
>> on the mountain.
>> And you better not fall cuz if you fall,
>> not going to be pretty.
>> This is a dangerous mountain. Rocky
>> mountain. I don't know if you can take
it this far.
>> Wow.
>> Yeah, you can do the parallel. Yes, you
can take it.
>> That's deep though.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. If we're call if we're called to
go preach
>> upon the mountains to those that are to
come out of Babylon,
>> we need to make sure that our feet are
as swift as rose that we don't get
we don't end up falling in Babylon and
with Babylon.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> Yeah, that's good. We we we definitely
better have dealt with our business
because uh we want to be able to say
like Jesus, you know, the prince of this
world cometh and hath nothing in me. I
better make sure there's nothing in
Babylon that I'm
>> hanging on to or triggered by or you and
and and you just for the record, Pastor
and Melinda, I will never read that
passage right there the same again. That
is something.
>> Yeah.
>> Wow.
>> Yeah. Beautiful.
>> Yeah, that's good. That's good. Uh,
we're at the end.
>> We're at the end of chapter.
>> Yep.
>> Completed it.
>> Yes. This was true Sabbath school in the
oldfashioned sense of it. I mean,
everybody
just having a panel, just having you
guys and everybody sharing and having
their bringing out their thoughts. Um,
it's beautiful. So,
our guest, you guys were amazing. our
panel. We We're thankful. Very thankful
for you.
>> Yeah.
>> Very thankful. And so we'll be on we're
gonna be moving into chapter four.
>> Yeah. So we're going to send out the uh
PDF for chapter 4.
>> Uh chapter four is entitled the spirit
of war.
>> And uh in this chapter, we're dealing
with the nine fruit of the spirit and
how they
>> how they connect with the spirit of war
for the Christian soldier. Amen.
>> And we actually did a did a series on
these on this. Uh
>> we did
>> um
>> several months ago.
>> Not months ago.
>> Yeah, I think it was
>> last year.
>> Well, that's months.
>> Wait. Oh, I don't know. This year kind
of You're right. It probably It was last
year. That still
>> Yeah, it started like in November
>> because this is actually Okay. About a
year ago.
>> Yeah.
>> I was We were in the middle of the
series when when Sean got sick.
>> Okay. Then it was longer than that.
>> Yeah. The fruit of the spirit. So we're
going through the nine, you know, the
nine fruit of the spirit. Every sermon
was on the next fruit. So um
>> we'll kind of pick up on that
>> uh and you know look at that in the
context of the Christian art of war um
in our next Sabbath school. So we'll get
the PDF out and um you all can follow
along. Yes, please follow along so that
when we um come back next week to do
this study, you will have already had
some of your thoughts and and u what
you're thinking and what God has shown
you uh when you were reading and doing
your study and so you can share in the
chat and you can be a part of this
amazing study that we are doing together
the Christian art of war and you can get
the PDF on mighty network. So again, if
you have not downloaded Mighty Networks,
which I remind you every single week to
do, you have to do it. Have to do it
today. And that and the link should be
in the chat, but we'll also have it up
again during uh the beginning of divine
worship.
>> All right.
>> Okay. So, let's pray.
>> Let's pray. Heavenly Father, thank you,
Lord, for giving us another opportunity
to uh consider this this uh fight of
faith. Lord, um we pray that those that
are listening, those that are watching,
and those that will see this in the
future, Lord, will be blessed, um and
will just be better equipped to fight
the good fight of faith, to fight the
battle against the greatest enemy, which
is self, Lord. And so, continue to bless
us in our understanding. Continue to
teach us um how to fight this fight of
faith is our prayer in Jesus name. Amen.
>> Amen. Amen. Stay tuned and continue to
worship with us.
[Music]
They say that difficult roads lead to
beautiful destinations. In no place have
I seen this to be truer than the
enchanting Indonesian island of
Nusapanita.
[Music]
Just 22 miles off the coast of Bali,
Nusa Panita is a world within a world
within a world. Visiting here is like
going back to the simple days of the
past. The roads are raw and the paths
are perilous, but the breathtaking views
and dreamy destinations are some of the
most awe inspiring my eyes have ever
seen.
There are so many natural hidden gems
scattered throughout the island. Both
far above and well below the surface,
you find a sweet sight for sore eyes.
One iconic destination is Killing King
Beach. Here, the wild turquoise sea
meets the golden sand, creating a
mesmerizing contrast. The sea cliffs
soar high above the secluded beach,
resembling the shape of a T-Rex
dinosaur. The ocean swells roll in from
two directions, clashing with the cliff
walls, creating mesmerizing movement and
peaceful patterns that inspire the
heart. The misty salt in the atmosphere
diffuses the light of the setting sun
and spreads a soft golden glow in the
atmosphere. It literally feels like
you're in a beautiful dream. It is one
of the most photogenetic places on
Earth. Each anguin perspective is like a
not geop picture, but to get there
requires an almost vertical climb up and
down a 600 ft cliff, a dangerous path.
Oh, but a dreamy destination.
As you go further and deeper into the
island, you'll be captivated by the
pristine beauty of Diamond Beach, the
romantic sunsets of Crystal Bay, the
creative coes of Broken Beach, the
triangled rocky pyramids of Utah Beach,
and the black manta rays that congregate
at the southwest point. From thrilling
adventures to aesthetic tranquility,
Nusup Panita offers a unique experience
for every traveler. From the mainland of
Bali, the only way to reach Nusup Panita
is a short trip by speedboat. Once
you're on the island, the only thing
left to do is explore. But not so fast,
because the thing that makes Nusup
Padita different is its rough roads. In
fact, this island has some of the most
dangerous roads in the world. When you
break away from the well-paved routes on
the main road and head to the remote
destinations, the path starts to get
really rough. These roads have fallen
victim to the harsh erosion. The paths
are full of potholes and steep drop
offs. Traveling on the roads of Nusa
Panita demands your full attention. The
twists and turns require you to be
hyperfocused. The steep inclines and
drop offs are super scary. The
unpredictable conditions of the roads
are constantly changing. Some parts may
be washed out or under construction.
Navigation can be sketchy with limited
cell phone service. To put it simply,
the rugged roads of Nusup Panita are not
for the faint of heart, nor for those
who are afraid of heights. There are no
guardrails, no street lights, no light
reflectors, and minimal street signs.
Most scary of all is that cars don't
mind taking up most of the space on your
side of the road. Staying in your lane
isn't an option here. There are many
blind corners and hardly any room for
oncoming traffic.
But these are the only paths that lead
to the gems all over the island. These
are dangerous roads, but these are the
roads to new revelations. The ways of
absolute wonder, perilous paths packed
with profound lessons for life. You see,
the roads of Nusup Paneda are in many
ways like the pathways of life. Each one
is different, each with its own unique
challenges and difficulties. But with
those chaotic conditions come new
opportunities for discovery and new
potential for growth. Some paths seem to
lead to nowhere. But each path has a
purpose and a lesson to teach. Each road
has a destination. Some may be more
spectacular than others. But each
destination has a different view with a
distinct revelation.
Hollow to whoever
cut these steps out of the mountain
because this view special.
[Music]
We go. Beautiful, beautiful
destinations, but dangerous paths.
Let's go explore some more.
Life is filled with different paths that
take form in different areas. career,
recreation, relationships, education,
and the many opportunities that come our
way. At times, we may find the path
paved and smooth with ease and comfort.
During these times of ease, we're
satisfied with serenity along these
stretches, making our hearts glad and
our spirits sore. But at some point we
will undoubtedly encounter roads with
potholes and ditches, challenges and
trials, headaches and heartbreaks, and
to navigate through the perilous and
unpredictable pathways of life. We must
remain hyperfocused, and we must learn
to adapt to its ever changing
conditions. At times, you might find
that one road isn't for you. That's
okay. You never know until you explore.
U-turns are permitted on the roads of
life. The point is this. Don't stay in
one place. No matter how beautiful the
view might be. There's still so much
more to discover and so much more to
experience in life. So don't be afraid
to try a new road. You never know who
you will meet along the way and what new
lesson that person is meant to teach
you. So get outside of your comfort zone
and don't allow the dangers of the way
to deter you from experiencing something
different and something new. Don't be
afraid to take the road less traveled
and learn to welcome and embrace new
encounters, new people, new ideas, new
discoveries with a brave heart and an
open mind.
[Music]
But just like the perilous pathways of
Nusup Padida that requires its explorers
to be mindful, we too need to be careful
when we head down the road of life. So
today I encourage you to keep your eyes
open for both the dangers and the
delights along the way. The more roads
you take, the greater will be your
perspective. The greater your
perspective, the broader your vision.
The broader your vision, the more
accurate your discernment. And the more
accurate your discernment, the greater
your gratitude and appreciation for
life. The more roads you travel, the
more you realize that there are some
destinations that only have one route.
Then there are other destinations that
have many ways to arrive. And if someone
gets to the same destination a different
way than you, it's okay. Just be
grateful that there's a path available
to all, no matter where they are in the
way. The more paths you travel, the more
you realize that we're all in this
together. And when we look upon each
other, not as competitors, but as fellow
travelers along the way, the journey
will be far more satisfying. So keep
exploring all the paths that God places
in front of you. Learn the lessons found
in every way, the easy ones and the hard
ones, too. And as you continue to move
forward in this journey called life, I
hope one day to see you along my way.
[Music]
What other lessons can we learn from the
beautiful island of Nusa Panita? Please
share in the comments below. And when
you have a minute, please check out the
rest of our episodes shot around the
world. Each is a unique and special
revelation, a perfect dose of
captivation, exploration, and
inspiration for your day. See more
episodes and partner with us at the
website below. Your monthly pledge will
empower us to continue to create
life-changing content for all. If you'd
like to join me on an epic excursion in
Hawaii, or create some meaningful
artistic imagery, vibe to the musings of
meaningful conversations, or see some of
my incredible views of nature and life,
check out my other websites here. And of
course, please connect with us on
YouTube, Instagram, and Facebook. Thank
you for your precious time, attention
and support. Aloha always. Mahalo and
Marinaf.
[Music]
Heat. Heat.
Welcome back Living Mana Church family.
We are so happy that you have decided to
stay with us today and continue to
worship with us. We are so happy to see
each and every one of you. Wasn't that
an amazing Sabbath school? I mean, the
book The Christian Art of War, it just
we are just unpacking that book chapter
after chapter. and to hear our Sabbath
school panel and all the insight that
they have and I have to tell you I love
our youth and when they share it just
brings a huge smile to my face and so it
is just a blessing to be going through
that book so methodically and so
precisely and slowly and hopefully you
are downloading uh the chapters
yourselves so that you are going through
it with us. It has been such a true
blessing. Please put in the chat where
you are viewing from. Uh we want our
viewing audience to say a special
welcome to you. And if this is your very
first time at Living Mana Church, please
put a one in the chat because I know our
viewing audience wants to know who's
here, who's new, where you're viewing
from. We love to see um all the
different places that people are viewing
from from around the country, from
around the world. It really uh here at
Living Mana Church um those of us who
who volunteer here and work here and
behind the scenes, it really uh makes us
joyful to see where everyone is viewing
from and to see how this church, this
First Seventh Day Adventist online
church is truly an international church
because we have people from everywhere.
So, please put in the chat where you're
viewing from. We're just so thankful
that you are here today. You know, I
want to teach you how to I shouldn't say
teach. I want to show you how you can
stay stay connected to Living Mana
Church. We want to be able to stay
connected to you and you stay connected
to us. We want to be able to tell you
what's going on during the week. We want
to remind you uh of different things.
I'll give you an example. Like I was it
was Sunday evening and I had forgot all
about the meetups. like that's our
social uh meetup uh group with different
groups and people from all around the
world all of our living mana church
people and um I was sitting there and
then I got a notification that said hey
meetups is going to start in about 10
minutes and I was like oh that's right
it is today so even I forget things that
are going to happen at living manage
church and so the reason why I got a
notification is because I signed up I
signed up three years ago so I would get
notifications three and a half years
ago. And so you can do the same. If you
have not signed up to get notifications
from Living Mana Church, I want you to
do that now because then you will get
the reminders when you forget something
uh that we're doing and that
notification that text comes across and
it helps you to remember. So, the way
that you can sign up to do that is you
can send a text to 855207-4107
and then that will automatically sign
you up. You can also scan that QR code
that is there that will um allow you to
sign up as well. And so that's how you
can get text alerts if you live here in
America from Living Mana Church. So
again, you could be reminded of our
programming and other announcements that
we have. If you are not, because I said
we're an international church, if you
are not here in America, you cannot get
those text messages. So you're going to
have to download Mighty Network. And if
you viewing audience, I don't care if
you're in America or internationally, if
you want to be a part of the Living Mana
Church family and form community and and
want to know everything that's happening
here at Living Mana Church, you are
going to want to sign up for Mighty
Networks. And the link is in the chat to
be able to do that. So, please do that
because that is our virtual church home.
you're not going to want to um miss
anything, especially if you're
international by not getting Mighty
Networks. But there at Mighty Networks,
you'll be able to see all the different
small groups that we have. You'll get to
see the leadership, you'll be able to
message them, and uh that's the way that
you're going to be able to stay
connected in that way. So, you
definitely want to sign up um for the
text alerts, and if you're out of
America, you definitely want to sign up
for Mighty Networks. But really, if even
if you're here in America, you still
want to sign up for mighty networks.
That's how you can get all the
information about living manage church.
Also want to remind you guys that we do
have kids programming and that's Lamos
Kids. We have amazing leadership that is
teaching and leading out with our kids
and they are learning the powerful
things in God's word. And so it's
amazing to see them in action and to see
what they've been learning. If you want
your child to be involved in LMOC kids,
please email LMC kids living mana.urch.
You can also text kids to that 855
number uh that's there on your screen.
And Eloci Kids starts at 11:30 central
time and they run for about 90 minutes.
So please get your kids involved in Elmo
Elos Kids. Also want to remind you guys
that Pastor Meyers does have virtual
church office hours. So if you are
wanting or needing to speak with Pastor
Meyers, please send an email to Patrice
at living mana.live for your appointment
and uh she will send you a link where
you will see all of Pastor Meyer's
availability and you will be able to
sign up right away if that matches your
availability. So that's how you can set
up a virtual meeting with Pastor Meyers.
want you guys to know that, drum roll,
exciting Mental Health Mondays is coming
back this Monday. And I'm excited
because I'm a host, but so is Dr.
Ricardo White. So, I want you to listen
to what he has to say about our first
program and the programming that we're
going to do this season, season 4. So,
check this out.
church family. Real life brings real
problems. Whether it's anxiety, burnout,
conflict, or tough decisions. This
season on Mental Health Mondays, we're
getting more problem focused than ever.
If you're dealing with it, we want to
have a show on it. I'm Dr. Ricardo
White, a board certified Christian
psychiatrist, and my co-host, Sister
Tante Meyers, a licensed marriage and
family therapist, are packing each
episode with clear, actionable steps you
can use before the credits start
rolling. Okay, maybe that's an
exaggeration, but we'll push the
envelope with special guests, and you'll
hear both lenses throughout the season,
a therapist perspective and a
psychiatrist perspective. Different
angles, but ideas based on a common love
for God. Your mind matters to God. Your
peace is worth a plan. So, join us for
Mental Health Mondays, starting this
Monday, September 15th, 700 p.m. Central
Standard Time. Bring a friend. Bring
your questions. But leave with tools
that work.
Wow. I love his t-shirt. Master your
mind, master your life. That I love
that. I love it. So, yes, please join us
this Monday. And if you got if you
signed up for the text alerts or mighty
networks, you will be reminded uh when
we go live. But I'm excited for season
four to bring you more mental health
Mondays. Also, just want to remind you
guys that we do um have two prayer
ministries that run on Wednesday evening
and um besides um just the our well we
have our power hour, our power line I
should say. Um and so that is our
evangelistic way of reaching out into
the community with uh prayer. Um, and
Power Wednesdays is also on Wednesday.
Uh, but the power line is something new
um that has been recently started and
that's 800 PM central right after Power
Wednesdays. And so what it is is that
people can um go to the YouTube channel,
they can put in their prayer request and
they will be prayed over right there
live. And so you can share with people
and say, "Hey, my church prays for
people every uh Wednesday live. So if
you put your prayer request or hey tell
them if you give me a prayer request I
will have them pray for you live right
on the spot and so people really do
appreciate that. So that's the power
line on Wednesday at 8:00 p.m. after
power Wednesday. Also want to remind you
guys that we have communion coming up
and that's going to be on October 31st
at 700 p.m. Central. You're gonna want
to scan that QR code uh because there
you'll see where you can order the juice
for communion and you can order uh the
bread for communion. Communion bread as
well. And you'll also see a recipe there
so that you can make your own communion
bread if you would like to. And so
again, communion's October 31st at 700
p.m. Central time. and you can just scan
that QR code and get all the information
that you are needing. We do have a uh
new small group that's uh starting and
that is healing hour and the healing
hour is kind of self-explanatory there.
Um, but you can see it's going to be
every first Sunday of the month at 12 PM
Central time and um it's going to be on
Mighty Network. So, and it's a small
group. So, if you're wanting to be a
part of that um you should definitely um
just get more information there, but
it's going to be hosted by uh Sister
Angela. So, all of that um is there for
you. It says, "If you or someone you
know is struggling with chronic illness,
the healing hour will meet every first
Sunday of the month at 12 PM Central
time. Be encouraged, learn to pray, get
resources, streng strengthen your faith,
get delivered, and watch God move. Glory
to God." And so, you're not going to
want to miss that. And it's going to be
again uh led out by Sister Angela. And
she's always a blessing uh whenever she
leads out anything. She is a true uh
blessing and so you are going to you
don't want to miss that. There's also a
need of volunteers here at uh living
mana church. They are needed. So we need
online greeters um those who can lead
out um for just and for digital small
group host benevolence committee welcome
committee um as you can see the text
alerts team. So we are needing
volunteers. So um you can find out more
information about that um by going to
mighty networks but living mana online
church is growing and so um it is the
need uh for hands hearts and help help
behind the scenes. From the tech to
teaching prayer production there's
places for your gifts to shine. If
you've been wondering how to get
involved now is the time. head over to
the service opportunities on Mighty
Networks to explore open roles and to
sign up. So, if you feel like you have
talents and gifts that can fit in to any
of these areas, uh please definitely go
over uh to that section in Mighty
Network so you can learn more. also true
health Tuesday. Uh just that is every uh
every other Tuesday uh night join Dr.
Maria Humel uh live for true health
Tuesday. Um you're let's see here you go
to to space for practical powerful and
forthrooted nutrition insights from
decoding food labels to reversing
chronic conditions. Dr. Dr. Hmel brings
decades of expertise and answers to your
questions to for in real time and she is
such a personable person and down to
earth and she's teaching you all of
these deep things and so definitely you
want to tune in to True Health Tuesdays
which is every other Tuesdays. All
right. And women's ministry
women's ministry also has amazing things
that are going on. Um, this mighty
network space um is for you to gather,
grow, and glow with the women's ministry
of Living Mana Online Church. Whether
whether you are prayer warrior, a quiet
storm, or just figuring it all out,
we've got a space for you. Expect real
talk, deep word, and a whole lot of joy
from devotionals and leadership uh
moments. We're we're building a
sisterhood that's rooted in grace and
ready to move mountains. So, if you want
to be be a part of this women's
ministry, you can send an email to women
living.urch
and you can also type women to that 855
number. You can text that uh as well and
you will get more information. But that
sounds exciting. If you want to be um in
a group of women um and have that
communion together, you definitely want
to be a part of the women's ministry.
Sounds exciting.
You know, we are just so thankful to be
here as a church for three and a half
years. It is just God has just been
amazing at what he has done. Uh we it
just it just amazes me still every
Sabbath and when uh we travel around the
country and the world and people just
say how they are blessed by Living Man
Church. We are just so thankful to God
and so thankful to you because of your
faithfulness uh just being here. Your
presence showing up praying for us and
your financial gifts um has really been
a blessing to the church. And if you
would like to continue to give, the way
that you can give virtually is to go to
adventistgiving.org.
Adventistsgiving.org. You can go there
and you will be able to click in the
right hand corner. You put in living
mana church in a virtual tithe envelope
will drop down. You'll see there all the
line items where you can give. Um you
can give your tithe and that goes to the
northeastern conference because living
mana church is a the church is a part of
the northeastern conference. you can
give to the local church uh budget which
there is where we are able to do all of
the things that Living Mana Church is
doing um and go and spreading this
gospel into all the world but also just
the practical things of you see all
these lights and cameras and everything
that we do to be able to have this type
of production quality production and go
into all the world and so the local
church budget um you can give to that to
support that you will see a benevolence
fund there which we are able to use that
to help people when they are in need and
asking for some assistance and you will
see other things on that tithe envelope
as well. So that is the way that you can
give virtually is to go to
adventistgiving.org.
If you would like to mail in a check
with your tithe and your offering, you
can send that to PO Box 428 Owensro
Alabama 35763.
But please write a little note uh in
there as well to let us know what is how
much is for tithe, what's for offering,
if you're giving to the benevolence fund
or to some other area because we want
your funds to go to the right place
where you want it to go. So again, we
are just so thankful uh for all of you
for supporting Living Mana Church again
with your presence, your prayer, and
your financial gifts. You have been so
faithful to God um and he has been so
faithful to us. And so we just want to
lift up a prayer of thanksgiving to him
at this time. So if you would just bow
your heads with me as we pray.
Heavenly Father, Lord, I just want to
thank you so much for this Sabbath day,
Lord. Want to thank you for the blessing
uh that Sabbath school was, Lord, and
just to have all of these viewers here
worshiping with us today. Lord, I know
there's many out there that are dealing
with health ailments, Lord. I pray that
you will heal them. Heal them. Touch
them. Give them peace. I want them to
feel your love and your comfort even now
while they are going through this. Lord,
there are so many that are going through
marital issues and family issues and
they just feel discouraged. I just Lord,
bless them today. Show them that you are
with them even again as they're going
through what they're going through.
Lord, show them what you want them to
do. um if there's something that they
can do to make this situation better.
Lord, I pray over the finances of the
viewing audience at this time. There are
some that are just Lord, they don't know
where their next meal is coming from or
they don't know how they're going to pay
the bills. Lord, bless them financially.
And Lord, I just pray that they will
have peace and trusting you and
believing that you are going to provide
all of their needs. Lord, I want to lift
up Pastor Meyers and the message that
you have given him for today that um it
will touch us in a special way that we
will not leave this church today the
same as we came in, but we will be
different spiritually. You will have
just spoken through your man's servant.
Lord, we thank you for this Sabbath in
Jesus name. Amen.
[Music]
We are church. We are redeemed and
chosen. Trusting in the God of love, the
God of hope, the God of atonement.
We are church. We believe in one way,
one truth, one life, devoted, eyes fixed
on the prize, devoted to Christ.
We are church. We put God first. We are
like-minded people created in Christ for
good works. Made in the image of
greatness. Made to reflect the greatest
love ever known.
We are church. The light in the dark.
The hope to the hopeless. A brand new
start. Peace for the broken heart. A
love that has open arms. We are church.
Not four walls. We are a body of
believers following the call. The call
to know we are forgiven. The call to
love without condition. The call to
trust without division.
We are church, a community with open
doors serving the poor, living for more.
We are broken people with a united cause
and unbroken love in a divided society
proclaiming Jesus is Lord.
This is what we do. We don't judge. We
don't hold a grudge. We are not perfect.
But we aspire to love.
We are church.
[Music]
I shall wear
a crown.
a crown
when it's all over.
When it's all over,
I shall wear
a crown.
a crown
when it's
all over.
Then it's all over.
I'm going to put on my road.
Tell the story
how I need it over.
I'm going to put on my ro.
Tell the story
how I made it over.
[Music]
Tonight
I get
home
soon.
I get
home.
[Music]
I shall see
his face.
[Music]
I shall see his face.
Oh,
when it's all over.
When it's all over.
I'm going to put on my robe
[Music]
it
over.
[Music]
a story
how I made it over.
Yeah.
Put on my robe
[Music]
it all
story
over
[Music]
it.
Soon
I get
home.
[Music]
Yeah.
Oh yes.
soon as
I
[Music]
here at Living Mana, we bear each
other's burdens. When you need support
or prayer, when you're feeling
discouraged
or alone or anxious,
you don't have to face life struggles
alone.
[Music]
Let us come boldly unto the throne of
grace that we may obtain mercy and find
grace to help in our time of need.
[Music]
The Lord is close to the brokenhearted
and saves those who are crushed in
spirit.
[Music]
Greetings saints of the most high God,
family, friends, everybody watching
today. Welcome to another edition of
Living Manners Prayer and Praise Time.
I'm Brother Terry here with my lovely
bride Amra. We are certainly thankful
and excited and and we say that every
week, but but we mean it.
>> We really are excited every week.
>> We really really really love living
mana. Love seeing you all. Love being
here with you all. Love being able to be
seen today because uh look, I don't know
about you, but when you read that story,
you hear that song, you ever have a
song, that one of those songs you hear
it, no matter how many times you hear
it, that song touches you the same way
every time. What an awesome song this
brother just sang. Uh, for some of you,
you I saw you were saying the volume's
too low. Sorry about that. We we really
apologize for that. We'll continue to
work on it and get better at that. But
in case you missed it, he said, uh, I
shall wear a crown.
>> Yeah. He says, "When it's all over, I'm
going to put on my robe and tell the
story of how I made it over." Man, what
a song.
>> What a song. For all of you that are
coming through your storms today, for
all of you that are holding on and
trusting Jesus, no matter what you see,
no matter what others say, no matter
what you feel, no matter what others
think, or no matter what you might think
sometime when the enemy try to get in
your head, when it's all over, saints.
Hallelujah. We see you there in the
chat. Greetings to you, our lovely
sister Annette. We see you, beautiful
sister. Sister Sharon,
>> Robert Plant.
>> Elder Elder Plant. Yes,
>> Nicole. Nicole on fire always. We see
you there. Happy Sabbath.
>> Um, John, I saw you earlier. John
Heasley, good brother. Still praying for
you and your family there in Ohio, I
believe.
>> Jackie, Danny, and Ayanna. Hello,
everyone.
>> Absolutely. Everybody, see you there.
Sister Crystal, good seeing you there.
Hanging on and working towards your
degree. We're keeping you in prayer,
>> everybody.
>> Hello, Trevor.
>> Trevor. Hey, brother Trevor. We love
you, my brother. So glad to see you here
with us today. Good soldier. Stay in the
fight.
>> Amen. Who else we got here?
Did I say sister Sharon Fay?
I did. Sister Sharon Fay, hello again.
Happy Sabbath, my sister. You, as you
know, you are in our hearts, beloved.
>> Hold on. Hold on. And continue to fight.
>> Um, look, I believe before we do praise
reports, we have a few special
birthdays, didn't we?
>> We have a couple birthdays. We sure do.
>> Who's having a birthday?
>> So, yesterday was Loami Richardson,
>> Pastor Loami. Happy birthday to you.
>> And many more.
>> Yes.
>> And today
is our very own Jodie Mccclure. Happy
birthday, Jod.
>> Sister Jodie. Love you. Love you. And
anyone else that's having a birthday in
the month that we didn't get. I mean,
send in your birthdays. Let us know
what's going on. So,
>> Absolutely.
>> I'll definitely make sure you get mine
ahead of time. So you can
>> His isn't for a while, folks.
>> Well, praise God.
It's coming. So you got to keep people
reminded of that.
>> It's not until February, but you know.
>> Hey, with the way time is flying, right?
February will be here before we know it.
>> I celebrate you every day. Okay.
>> Praise God.
>> All right.
>> Amen. I'm celebrating you, too, my love.
And
>> All right.
>> Brother Graham Henry Jr., we see you
there, my brother. Prayer warrior.
>> Christiey's birthday was yesterday. Oh,
sister Christie.
>> Happy birthday, Christie.
>> My sister from South Carolina.
Definitely. We love you. And all of my
South Carolinians watching today, shout
outs to all of y'all. We love you there
in Carolina. I know that Sister M uh uh
uh uh uh
Ashley's in South Carolina.
>> Ashan Owens.
>> Yes. Ashley and John are in South
Carolina. Uh we have a few Carolinians
here. Uh Laya and Wes are in North
Carolina. So to the Carolinas,
happy Sabbath to you.
Oh, the other sister uh from South
Carolina.
Sister Wright is in South Carolina. So,
praise God.
>> Terry is from South Carolina. For all
those who are wondering why he's
shouting out South Carolina, that is
where he was born and raised. So,
>> that's right. That's right.
>> Absolutely.
>> So, praise the Lord, saints. Uh look, we
just want to make sure we mention today
to uh uh I always I want to keep in
prayer everybody that's going through
particular struggles. Those of you who
have shared some praise reports with us
of how God has moved and blessing your
life, we are very encouraged by that.
Denise shared a powerful testimony of
how the Lord uh allowed her to pray over
her own knee when she went to the
women's conference, her and Sister
Sheila. And sister Sheila was giving us
live updates and how the Lord just
healed her. And she said even before the
healing year, the Lord said, "Get up and
walk." And she walked down to the
conference. So beautiful stuff, saints.
And when the Bible says you shall lay
hands on the sick, that means you, too.
If you're sick, sometimes you got to
encourage yourself. Amen. In the Lord,
you got to lay hands on yourself. You
got to believe for yourself and rise up
in Jesus' name. So, that was a beautiful
testimony. Brother Jesse shared a
powerful testimony this morning. I like
Candi's testimony of of how the Lord
just allowed her today to just, you
know, say, "Look, sometimes I get in my
own way and get in my head, but it's
really about the Lord and what he's
doing and not about me." So, saints,
remember your purpose. No matter what
you're going through, ask the Lord to
reveal, Lord, what's your purpose in all
this because once we know what he's
doing, praise God, we can we can endure
and we can hold on.
>> Amen.
>> Well, all right.
>> Absolutely. Listen,
Sister Imagigene, I see you there. Don't
Sister Immaigene, right, is definitely
from South Carolina. And and when I
talked to her on the phone, you know,
Sister Imagigene sounds just like my
mom.
>> Oh, I said she had a birthday on the
28th.
>> Well, Sister Imagigene, we didn't even
know. Happy birthday to you, my beloved
sister.
>> Yes.
>> Amen. Praise God. It was on the 20. All
right. She put that South Carolina fire.
What that means is it's very hot there
in Carolina. I know. All right. All
right. Well, listen, saints. Um, we're
we're we're fellowshipping. We love
y'all. We want to say we love y'all.
Again, thank y'all so much for praying
for us. God is bringing us through. He's
bringing us through. Absolutely. And,
um, one of the things he's showing us is
that even if your circumstances don't
change right away, you can change. And
the purpose of the struggle sometimes
might not be that the circumstances
change, but that you change. And so God
in our trials have been changing us in a
lot of ways and drawing us closer to him
and closer to one another. And really we
appreciate the good times. So uh thank
you and we appreciate your prayers. We
really have felt your prayers. Uh I
don't have time right now but maybe
sometimes I'll tell you about some of
the miracles that have happened in my
life. The Lord literally saved my life
during this time and when y'all were
praying and I knew it was the prayers of
the saints. Emmer's had things happen
and she knew it was the prayers of the
saints. So, keep praying, saints. Don't
stop praying.
>> Absolutely.
>> Don't stop praying. Don't stop
believing. Don't stop surrendering.
Um, I got to send a special shout out to
our little warette, Melinda, and all
those involved in LMC kids. The great
work y'all doing. Friday Night Lights.
Got to send a shout out to all of y'all.
The M&M's, uh, Michaela, uh, uh, our
sister, uh, from Tanzania, Kazia from
Tanzania, Sister Kennedy, and all of you
young people. Listen, when we hear
someone like Melinda on fire like that,
it is to be an encouragement to us
because Elahu in the book of Job said
that, you know, I thought that, you
know, multitude of years should teach
wisdom and multitude of days should
teach knowledge and understanding. But
there's a spirit in man and the
inspiration of God gives them the
Almighty. The inspiration of the
Almighty gives them understanding.
Excuse me. And so what that shows us is
that God's spirit is available to every
one of us who want to yield ourselves to
him and receive it. because I'm being
taught by this precious young warrior.
She is bringing out some stuff and she's
letting the Lord really really transform
her thinking to think biblically. So,
uh, praise God for her. I had to give
her that shout out cuz, man, absolutely,
>> what a Sabbath school.
>> Okay,
>> it was a great one.
>> All right.
Well,
before I read our praise reports today,
just a reminder that if you have a
prayer request for a praise report that
you would like to submit for us to pray
over or that I can read during um the
program, please send an email to
praymanana.urch
and your prayers will be prayed
throughout the week.
If you would like to join the prayer
team or a special ops team under the
prayer team umbrella,
please also send an email to the same
address at praymmanana.urch.
If you're requesting a special ops team
for yourself or a loved one, please send
an email to spec ops. That's s pc ops
livingmana.urch.
If you would like to join the women's
ministry on mighty networks, please send
an email to women livingmana.urch.
And finally, if you would like to join
the men's ministry, please send an email
to sevenloaves. That's sen
l o a velomana.urch.
Well,
we have two praise reports today.
The first one coming from Robert Plant.
>> Amen. Elder Plant.
>> My uncle Willie Charles Webster had the
malignant mass removed and with the love
and support of the extended family, he
is set to undergo radiation and chemo.
Y'all will make a way.
>> Hallelujah. Amen. Will he
>> from Regina B.
Praise report. God moved an obstacle out
of my way at work and I thank him with
all my heart for that and the peace that
came with it.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> And that concludes the the praise
reports this week because we didn't have
a lot of submissions, but we praise God
for those two for sure.
>> Amen. Please remember if you would like
to submit your praise reports. We are
always looking forward to reading what
God is doing in your life. And I I know
it encourages and gives other people
hope as they are looking to the Lord for
answers. So please don't forget to
submit the praise reports because
praising God is what we do here at
Living Mana.
>> Yes. And um
>> yeah,
>> it's answer. It's answer to prayer. And
we always like to hear what the answer
was. So
>> yeah, and it's like that song we just
heard, you know, um when it's all over,
I'm going to put on my robe and tell the
story. Now listen, we're going to have
eternity to tell the story. Don't don't
don't don't think for one minute that
you'll be sitting there the whole time
just listening to good stories. You'll
be able to look back over your life and
see the record of how Jesus was there
the whole time. saving and unfolding and
moving things out the way and saving in
ways that we never even knew about. And
he's got to look back and say, "You
remember that? Well, what about that?
You remember that? You didn't even know
that was me doing all that work, you
know." And so, thank God uh that
everybody's got a story. May the spirit
of the Lord lay upon your hearts. uh the
different ways he's moving in and around
our lives.
>> You know, just to reflect off those
words, I didn't really know the Lord,
like truly know the Lord, till I was
probably 30 years old, until I
understood what a personal relationship
really looked like. I have a very
colorful religious history.
>> I'll share sometime. But anyways,
you know, I look back at my life and
even in my early 20s when I just
denied
>> Yeah.
>> having that relationship, I could see
him there like looking back like how he
strategically placed me in certain
places, locations, jobs. He had people
inter intersect in my life that spoke
Jesus into my life so many ways and uh
the journey is a tumultuous one at times
but it is an amazing and beautiful
journey with Jesus. So I'm just thankful
and grateful for everything that he's
done way before I even knew him.
>> Amen. Amen. So praise God everybody. And
so uh that is even one way the Lord
deepens our relationship with him, our
love for him, our trust for him is when
he allows us to look back over our lives
even before we uh uh entered into uh a
saving relationship with him. We can see
where he was saving us,
>> you see. And so ah friend, that stick is
closer than a brother. No other friend
like the lovely Jesus. Can we say amen,
saints?
>> Amen.
>> No other friend like the lovely Jesus.
Oh, Christy said she was also 30 years
old when I finally started following
Jesus and my 30-year amazing journey.
>> So, you see that saints, send in your
praise reports, send in your story
lines, and we will share them right
here. And also, look forward to seeing
more warriors uh joining us uh for
prayer. Uh we have a special warrior
that's going to join us here in just a
moment. But I did want to make sure that
I didn't neglect this.
I do want to ask that together we would
remember to pray for the Kirk family and
for uh uh Christian Kirk's bride and his
children, those who love them and that
were close to him. Especially us
Adventists, we ought to be the foremost
in showing the love of Jesus when it
comes to uh people disagreeing with you
about what you believe or something you
may say. Because let me tell you,
according to prophecy, the whole world's
about to be arrayed against us for what
we believe. And we will not be moved
because what we believe is based upon
the living word of God. And heaven and
earth shall pass away, but not this word
right here. And so let's let's let's um
pray for them in love and and ask God
fill our hearts and our mouths with
words of grace in Jesus name.
>> Yeah. you know, Charlie Kirk's wife, his
children, and then on my heart also was
the shooter's parents and and his family
because can you even imagine what
they're going through as well, their
young son in their 20s making such a
devastating
uh decision and having to live with
that. So,
>> yeah,
>> please keep both families in prayer.
>> Absolutely. Absolutely. Um, and so, uh,
thank y'all, uh, God's people of God, we
are, we are here to be the hands and
feet of Jesus and to show the heart of
Jesus in everything we say and do. God,
help us, help us to stay focused in this
evil world we're living in. And, um, we
want to now bring on a dear brother, a
dear warrior, a dear friend, a dear
servant, servant leader, man of God. I
truly admire and love this brother. He's
going to come on and lead us. um uh in
intercessory prayer church and uh if he
doesn't catch all of your prayer
requests know he's working hard uh back
there to get them all and our prayer
warriors are collecting prayer requests
as well. Thank you to sister Pauline
Sham Goodline and sister Christina for
always collecting the prayers and
disseminating them weekly through all of
the living men of prayer warriors. So,
brother Elco is going to come join us
and uh brother Elco, thank you and God
bless you as you come, my brother.
>> Okay,
good morning everyone. Good afternoon
everyone. Hope you can hear me now and
uh I'm leading you into ancestral
prayers and uh I want to ask you to bow
your heads and uh go and pray with me.
Dear heavenly father, Lord God, we come
before your throne of grace there father
with a thankful heart. Father, with a
thankful heart that we can celebrate
this day with you in freedom, Father,
that we are here gathering together on
your Sabbath day, Father, that we can be
placed in your rest, that we can
experience your rest, and that we can
gather together, Father, and be here as
one family, Father, joining together in
your presence, dear Lord. Before we
start praying, Father, we want to ask
you to forgive our shortcomings, to
forgive our sins, Father. To forgive
everything we did not said well or
right, whether we meant it or didn't
meant it, Father God. Father, when we
have hurt other people, whether we have
done wrong, other people, Father, please
forgive us, dear Lord. Father, before we
continue prayer, Father, we want to lift
up the family of uh uh of of um uh
Charlie Kirk, Father, and his family,
especially his wife and kids, Father.
His parents, Father, uh the
grandparents, the families around him,
Father, the the family-in-law, dear
Lord, they are affected directly, dear
Lord. They are in grief, Father. They
have to carry this their whole lives,
Father God. Father, we want to lift them
up, Father, in your presence, Father.
Father, regardless how we think and how
we will, they these are your children
too, Father. They al also belong to you,
Father God. We want to present them
before your throne of grace, Father, and
ask you to be with them, carry them
through, Father God, and hold them tight
to your hearts, Father. And please Lord
please Lord surround them and and and
and during the time of grief father
during this time of loss father that
they have to miss their uh uh uh spouse
father miss their dad's father their son
their their grandson their son-in-law
father or a best friend father all who
are direct directly uh in it in this
inner circle father god be with them and
carry them through dear lord father god
we want to continue father with prayer
requests which we found in the chats
father of our brothers and sisters our
family father our friends dear lord
father god we want to lift up brother or
sister do father our do father he asks
or she asks for prayer for the coming
month that he or she will be wiser in
Christ stronger in his pursuit of his
righteousness father unyielding in his
uh seeking his faith and showing his
love before all. Father God, we also
want to pray for our sister Takara who
uh who who asks to be more spiritual
fit. Father, a stronger she has a
stronger desire to exercise uh
consistently and uh continue uh
constantly. Father God, we also ask for
sister Lila Peterson, Father of
Peterson, Father, um for for work
family, for for continue uh uh God's
will for her and her family. Father,
Father God, also brother Leon, Father,
he is dealing with some ne nagging
headache. Father, please Lord, have your
hands on his head, Father, on that place
where it hurts, where it's where it
where it is nagging as he said. Dear
Lord, you know what a place is. Father,
you can have your hands on him. Father,
give him relief, Father. Give him such a
relief that he can enjoy today's uh
Sabbath day. Father, that he can be in
your rest and can relax, Father, but
also can uh focus on your word, Father.
Be with him, carry him through, dear
Lord. Father God, we also ask for BSG,
Father. Um they asked for their brother
uh uh brother Bobby who fell backward in
the bus uh by abrupt thing of the bus
stopping of the bus and he fell on his
back in the bus and it and it hurts
father. Father God lay your hands on the
back father and give relief dear lord so
that that he can move and and doesn't
feel the pain and that much father god.
Father, we also pray for our dear sister
Charlotte. Father, Father, we we
appreciate her as as I appreciate this
sister, Father God. She is such a strong
woman, dear Lord. And she write reminds
me of my own mother and of my own uh u
aunt, Father. Uh she is an amazing
woman, Father. the spirit she has,
Father. I want to lift her up, Father.
Not only for healing her colitis, but
and but continuing only for that,
Father, but also for her spirit, dear
Lord, for her strength, Father. That she
how she shows that to the brothers and
sisters, to this family, Father, despite
all things she's going through, Father,
that she keeps up, dear Lord. Father,
that she has some ministries, Father. We
know of her ministries in Pakistan,
Father, her devotion for that, Father
God, to have other people in other
countries, dear Lord, to to to be a
light for them, Father, to be for them
there, Father, and to work with them,
dear Lord. Father God, we want to bring
her before your throne of grace, Father,
and ask for a special prayer for her.
Ask for special attention for her,
Father. Not because it is her, because
she is your child, Father. and and
everyone has uh is is also
uh uh placed before your shoulder. I I
want to lift up the dear sister
Charlotte Father for this for this
prayer father. also for all the prayers
what just posted on the prayer walls.
Father, there's posting everywhere has
posted prayers, Father, in our
congregation in on on all the channels
we have, Father, in in on the prayer
walls, on the prayer chats, on the the
private chats, the private prayers,
Father, all those who who who pray for
all the prayer warriors who pray for
others and have also their own lists.
Dear Lord, Father God, we want to bring
those before your throne of grace also,
Father.
that the Holy Spirit also bring them
before your throne, Father, and make it
as a well smelling uh uh incense, dear
Lord, for your throne. Father God, we
also pray for sister uh Jodie
uh that the that her dad's second
hospital procedure on Monday, Father, uh
will rece uh will uh that he will
receive some more relief, Father,
Father, than the first time he went. He
got some relief father but father god be
with them be with the teams uh you know
what needs to be done dear lord you know
what what he needs and what the team of
medical uh team needs father and also
what your role in it is father father
god give him more relief and be with him
dear lord we also ask for Ellen father
for her three daughters uh her children
uh for her daughter and her the three
children of the daughter father to be
able uh to keep their home. Father, we
want to lift up this uh family, dear
Lord, with the with the three children,
Father. Father God, that they may have
your attention, Father, that you may
guide them, Father, that you may give
them insight, that you may show them
which way they have to walk, Father.
That the Holy Spirit, Father, can touch
their hearts, Father, and touch their
ears, Father, so they can hear you in
the spirit, dear Lord. Father God, guide
them through and be with them. Father,
Father, we also ask prayer for um uh
Esita White, Father, for her family and
herself.
Uh and and she they are in need of a
spiritual healing, but also physical
healing. Father, you know in what way
you know how to deal with that. You know
how to lift them up. You know where to
touch them and to heal them, dear Lord,
and get them on the right path, Father,
on the right track. the Lord be with
them and and and let the Holy Spirit
touch their hearts, Father. Let the Holy
Spirit guide them and lead them and that
they will be able to to uh to hear the
voice of you, Father God. Also, Verette,
Father, her three sons, CJ, Blake, and
Jacob, Father, surround them in the in
in his shield, Father, in the shield of
of Jesus Christ protection. and may no
weapon formed against uh them shall uh
prosper in Jesus' name. Dear Lord,
Father God, I saw my dear brother
Trevor. Father, how he was asking for
prayer for for his sister. Father God,
what an amazing brother this is, Father.
Despite everything he is going through,
dear Lord, he is asking for his sister,
for the social um uh um for the social
needs, Father, for for his sister, dear
Lord. But we also want to bring brother
Trevor, Father, before your throne of
grace, Father. We miss this brother in a
man's ministry, dear Lord. He is always
present, Father. But we miss him, Father
God. And and we want to let him know
that he is loved, that he is uh one of
the brothers, Father. That he belongs to
the brothers uh of of the living mana
family. Father, Father God, we want to
lift him up despite where he's going
through, Father. You know you you got
him. You have him. You you are carry him
through, Father. And you you surely love
him, Father. Please, Holy Spirit, touch
his heart and be with him. Touch him,
Father, so that he doesn't have to uh uh
to wonder whether you love him or not,
Father. But you love him, Father. You
got him and you love him. Your love is
so so great, Father. Also for him, we
want to lift him before your throne of
grace, Father, into your light and ask
you to hold him close to your heart,
Father God. be with him, Father, and
carry him through, Father. Father, we
also want to have our brothers and
sisters who who had their birthday,
Father, yesterday, today. Uh we think
about Pastor Loami, Sister Christy,
Sister Jodie, Sister Emojene, but also
for our little sister,
the the daughter of our beloved brother
Jesse. Father, Father God, maybe no one
had had seen it, but brother Sun gazing,
Father, is our beloved brother Jesse,
dear Lord. And Messi is his young is is
is his daughter, Father, who turned six
today, Father. What an amazing day for
this young young lady, for this young
princess, Father, for your little child,
Father, who is your child, dear Lord.
Father, we want to lift up Messi before
your throne of grace, dear Lord. And
Father God, give her that brightness.
Give her that smile on her face. Father,
be that light in her and through her so
that she can be a light not only for
herself but also for her parents and for
her siblings. Dear Lord, be with her.
Father, this we heard sometimes we heard
them smile. We heard them in the prayer
sessions. Father, coming through with
brother Jesse. Father, this is such a
lovely child. Dear Lord, we want to lift
her up before your throne of grace.
Father God also, brother, sister Dub
asked for her cousin or his cousin
Gregory. Father, he he's still battles
with cancer. Uh we we ask to continue
our prayers for him. Uh Father, to be
with him, to carry him through, to
enlighten him, Father, to but also to
soften the pain and and be with him,
dear Lord. Father God, carry him in
these these times, but make things a bit
light for him, but also have your
healing hands on him. Dear Lord, be with
the medical teams, Father God. Surround
him with your love and and your
presency, dear Lord. Family Joy uh um
Tom Joyce,
I think it's I I wrote it wrong. My my
handwriting is sometimes. Father Joyce
Fisher, family members, uh who who deal
with alcohol issues. Father, we want to
lift those brothers or sisters up before
your throne of grace. Father, we know
how difficult that is, Father. That they
may may seek help, Father. Father, but
also in our church, Father, there are
small groups. I I mentioned the group
staff, Father, who who are specially
trained in in guiding and leading people
with with alcohol issues, dear Lord.
Father God, let their hearts be touched
and let them contact, Father, the star
group, dear Lord, because they are
dedicated brothers and sisters who are
able to help. You know them, Father.
Bring them in contact with each other,
dear Lord. Jodi Mccclure, I ask also for
all the El Moses students, Father, and
uh that they will reach out for our Lord
through their ministries, dear Lord.
Father, we lift up El Moses, this
classes of uh the LOC church. Father,
and all those who are following the the
first uh um who is the first group,
Father, guide those uh brothers and
sisters. Help them with getting their
ministry and ministries in place and so
they can serve in the field. Dear Lord,
Father God, we all bring all these
prayers, Father, before your throne.
only there's one prayer father I want to
bring up father of sister Julian father
and her family and her son in the
Netherlands dear lord father we want to
lift her up her family up father guide
them through you know what they're
dealing with you know what their needs
are father lay your hands upon this
beautiful family dear lord and guide
them through father uh be with their
hearts and give them rest and peace dear
lord father guide them guide the son in
the Netherlands uh and and and dear Lord
be with them. We ask you, Father, our
Holy Spirit
to gather all these prayers and all the
silent prayers which were done just now
on the sidelines and in the field,
Father God. Father, that
the Holy Spirit will bring these prayers
before your throne of grace as a well
smelling incense, Father, in Jesus' name
we pray all this. Amen.
Amen. Thank you, brother Elco. And thank
you, saints of the most high God for
joining us for prayer. We're now
preparing for the word of God. And we
prayed, Lord, bless this word today. May
our hearts be attentive. May our minds
be alert, Lord. May your word bring
forth fruit and a harvest, Lord God, to
your glory, honor, and praise in Jesus
name.
>> Amen.
tears so sweet.
Trust in Jesus
just to take him
at his word,
just to rest
upon his promise.
Just to know
I said the Lord oh
[Music]
Jesus
how I trust him.
How I prove him
more and more. Oh
Jesus. Oh Jesus.
Precious Jesus.
Oh, for grace to trust him more. Oh,
I so glad I learned to trust him.
Precious Jesus,
Savior and friend, and
just to rest. Yeah. upon his promise
that he will be with me until
the end. Oh
Jesus. Yeah, Jesus.
How I trust him
and how I prove him
more and more. Oh Jesus.
Oh Jesus.
Precious
Jesus.
Oh for grace
to trust him more. Oh
hallelujah Jesus.
How I trust him.
How I prove him
more and more. Oh Jesus.
Oh Jesus.
Precious
Jesus.
Oh, for grace
to trust
him more. Oh,
glory to your name.
How I trust him.
How I prove him
more and more. Oh Jesus.
Hallelujah. Jesus,
precious
Jesus.
Oh, for grace
to trust him. Now this is your turn. Oh
Jesus.
Jesus,
how I trust him.
Oh, y'all didn't think I would check.
[Music]
Oh Jesus.
Jesus.
Oh y'all how I trust him.
[Music]
Oh, for grace
to trust him more.
Just a little bit more grace.
[Music]
Just a little bit more grace. If I could
have a little bit more. Yeah. Yes. Oh,
for grace.
Oh, for grace
[Music]
to
trust.
[Music]
To trust
him
[Music]
more.
More
[Music]
Amen. And happy Sabbath everyone. Um, I
want to welcome you to Living Mana
Online Church. We are getting ready to
get into the word of God today. And I
pray that, uh, today's message will
speak to your heart in a very special
special way. So, uh, today's message is
entitled I Unfriend You: Satan's
Dehumanization Plot for the End Times.
Pray with me, please. Heavenly Father,
we ask in a special way, Lord, that you
would please speak through me today.
Lord, please open the eyes of your
people. And Lord, help us to know not
only what is the enemy's plan, but what
is your plan for us as well. And Lord,
may we follow that plan is our prayer in
Jesus name. Amen.
I unfriend you. Satan's deum
dehumanization plot for the end times.
That phrase I unfriend you is a very
familiar phrase especially in our social
media um saturated world. Uh we unfriend
people
uh if we don't like what someone has
said. We unfriend people if we feel that
they have come at us in a in a wrong
way. And it is not something limited to
social media. It is something that is
happening all the time. I unfriend you.
I want to take that particular theme,
that particular thought, and I want to
trace something through the Bible for
you that by the grace of God, you will
you will have the curtains pulled back
to see what the enemy's plan is for
God's people, especially as it relates
to the end of time. So, let's go to the
screen. We're going to begin with John
chapter 15. John chapter 15, verse 12.
Jesus said these words, "This is my
commandment that you love one another as
I have loved you. Greater love has no
man than this, that a man lay down his
life for his friends. You are my friends
if you do whatsoever I command you." You
can see here that Jesus puts a high
value on friendship and he connects
friendship with love. He says, "Greater
love has no man than this than a man is
willing to lay his life down for his
friends." Friendship in God's eyes is
connected with love. Now, what I want to
show you, beloved, requires us to go
back to the book of Genesis,
uh, when God is is is creating the
world. And we're going to look at
Genesis chapter 1, uh, particularly
verse 24. In verse 24, the Bible says
these words. And God said, "Let the
earth bring forth the living creature
after his kind, cattle and creeping
things, and the beasts of the earth
after his kind." And it was so. And God
made the beast of the earth after his
kind, and cattle after their kind, and
everything that creepeth upon the earth
after his kind. And God saw that it was
good. Now, Genesis 1:es 24 and 25 are
speaking to God's creating of the beasts
of the earth. And immediately after he
creates the beast of the earth, the text
now goes on to say these words, verse
26. And God said, "Let us make man in
our image, after our likeness, and let
them have dominion over the fish of the
sea, and over the fowl of the air, and
over the cattle, and over all the earth,
and over every creeping thing that
creepeth upon the earth." So God created
man in his own image, in the image of
God created he him, male and female
created he them. Verse 28, "And God
blessed them. And God said unto them,
"Be fruitful and multiply, and replenish
the earth, and subdue it, and have
dominion over the fish of the of the
sea, and over the fowl of the air, and
over every living thing that moveth upon
the earth." What I want you to
understand here is that there is a
difference between the creation of beast
and the creation of man. Man was made in
the image of God. Beasts were not made
in the image of God. put a one in the
chat that if you're following so far,
very simple point. When God made beasts,
they were not made in the image of God.
But when he made when God made beasts,
they were not in the image of God. But
when he made man, they were in the image
of God. Now, what does it mean that we
were made in the image of God? Um, and
beasts were not. Well, notice with me
John 1, 1 John 1:4,
where the Bible says these words, "He
that loveth not knoweth not God, for God
is love." If God is love, and man was
made in the image of God, then what that
means is man was made with this
beautiful capacity to love.
It is something that beasts do not
possess. Beasts don't know how to love.
Beasts don't know how to have empathy.
Beasts don't know the qualities of a
human life. And so, man was made
specifically in the image of God.
Meaning, man was made h with the
capacity to love. So, let's get that
straight. The beasts had no capacity to
love. Man was made with the capacity to
love.
Now the Bible says something interesting
in Genesis chapter 3. After God has
created man, tells man not to eat from
the tree. In Genesis 3:1,
the Bible says these words. Now the
serpent was more subtle than any beast
of the field which the Lord God had
made. And he said unto the woman, "Yay,
has God said, Ye shall not eat of every
tree of the garden." So now we have the
introduction of this serpent whom we
understand to be Satan. But this serpent
is described as a beast.
That is significant.
Uh uh the Bible tells us as the story
continues on that that Adam and Eve
ultimately listen to this beast and they
eat from the tree and now God is going
to come to them in the garden and God is
going to speak to Adam, to Eve and the
beast. And I want you to notice what he
says in Genesis 3:14.
The Bible says here, "And the Lord God
said unto the serpent." So now he's
talking to the serpent, "Because you
have done this, you are cursed above all
cattle, and above every beast of the
field, upon thy belly shalt thy go shalt
thou go, and dust shalt thou eat all the
days of thy life." And now watch this
next verse. Verse 15.
and I will put enmity between thee, that
is the serpent, this beast, and the
woman. So, we've got two categories here
being cursed.
The beast
I I shouldn't say being cursed, but two
categories that God is speaking to here
in this verse. The beast and the woman.
A and in verse 15 he says I will put
enmity between thee that is the beast
and the woman and between thy seed and
her seed.
That's very important to understand you
guys because what the text is telling us
here is that the beast itself
would have offspring.
In other words, this offspring
of the beast would would would
represent the seed of the beast. It
would be beast seed.
So in this in this uh uh uh prophecy
you have offspring of the beast and you
have offspring of the woman. One is
animal, one is human. Now we understand
that that that what is being spoken
about here in the context of both of
these seed are human beings. But please
note the significance.
One set of human beings
are going to be beastly
and the other set of human beings are
going to be human.
Human heart versus beast heart.
Human characteristics.
characteristics made in the image of God
versus beastly characteristics.
And so
what I want you to see here is this in
John chapter 3, 1 John chapter 3 11,
we're going to see something very
powerful here.
Before we go there, remember this that
Eve's first child is Cain.
And and Cain, we know, comes to
represent the seed of the beast.
Even though he's born of Eve, he's
actually the seed of the beast. Meaning
his character, his disposition was very
beastlike, animallike. And notice with
me 1 John 3:1 where the Bible says, "For
this is the message you have heard from
the beginning, that we should love one
another, not as Cain." No, watch this
now, guys. Watch. See the parallel here.
Love is of God.
And then it the text goes on to say,
"Not like Cain or not as Cain."
And watch this. who was of that wicked
one and slew his brother. And wherefore
slew he him because his own works were
evil and his brothers righteous. Marvel
not, my brethren, if the world hates
you. See that connection there? Cain
hates
God
love. The text literally says Cain was
of the wicked one. Let's go to the
screen and you'll see that that word of
in the Greek is simply X meaning out of
a primary preposition denoting origin
an action proceeding from or out of a
place.
In other words, beloved,
what the text is saying is that Cain was
of or proceeded from the serpent.
He was serpent seed.
Y'all put a one on the tell if you're
following so far. Abel represented the
seed of the righteous. Cain represented
the seed of the wicked. He was anim
animalistic.
Cain was animal seed. In other words, if
we can say it this way,
Cain represents those made, listen
carefully to me all, Cain represents
those made in the image of the beast,
while Abel would represent those made in
the image of God. Put a five in the chat
if you're following so far.
Put a five in the chat if you're
following so far. Now, I want you to
notice the nature of beast. In Psalms
80:13, for example, God is here
describing uh how Israel is his vine and
what's going to happen to his vine. And
he says here in verse 13, the bore out
of the wood doth waste it, and the wild
beast of the field doth devour it.
Talking about devouring God's people.
Beasts devour. Beasts kill. Beasts act
off of instinct. Notice with me Job
chapter 38:39.
Wilt thou hunt the prey for the lion or
fill the appetite of the young lions
when they couch in their dens and abide
in the covert to lie and wait? The
nature of a beast is to hunt, is to
pounce, is to look for something to
devour.
Y'all put a one in the chat if you're
following.
Put a one in the chat if you're
following. The nature of the beast is to
look for something to devour. In other
words, let me say it this way. When Cain
adopted or took on the nature of the
beast, he was dehumanized.
Put a six in the chat. Six in the chat.
Pastor, we get you. We're following you.
Cain was dehumanized. He didn't take on
the image of God. He took on the image
of the beast. And in taking on the image
of the beast, he was dehumanized.
How do we know this? If we go back to
Genesis 4:5, uh the Bible says, "But
unto Cain," so remember Cain and Abel
both bring an offering unto God. And the
Bible says, "But unto Cain and to his
offering, God had not respect. And Cain
was very wroth, and his countenance
fell." The single indicator
of reflecting the image of the beast is
wrath
is anger.
Cain became angry. It is the sign. It is
the first signal. It is the first
characteristic
of those who have the image of the
beast.
Cain gets angry
and his anger
is now going to be directed somewhere.
You see,
in Ephesians chapter 6:12, we're told
this, "For we wrestle not against flesh
and blood, but against principalities,
against powers, against the rulers of
the darkness of this world, against
spiritual wickedness in high places."
God's people, those who walk in the
image of God, recognize this crucial
truth that we wrestle not against flesh
and blood. In other words, flesh and
blood is not the real enemy.
You should never look at any any human
being and think that human being is my
enemy. Flesh and blood is my enemy. The
Bible says that the spiritual understand
that flesh and blood is not the enemy.
We don't wrestle against flesh and
blood. But note what Cain does. Come
with me to Genesis 4:6. The Lord said
unto Cain, "Why art thou wroth, and why
is thy countenance fallen? If thou doest
well, shalt thou not be accepted? And if
thou doest not well, sin lith at the
door." Some translations say, "Sin
crouches
at the door."
So now God is using animal language.
Sin like a beast is wanting to pounce on
you, Cain.
But Cain, I want you to rule over this
thing. Understand Cain that your enemy
is not your brother. Your enemy is not
your brother.
It would have been a beautiful thing if
this guy by the name of Tyler, I don't
remember his last name, if he understood
that as off as he may have thought
Charlie Kirk was, that it was not flesh
and blood. Flesh and blood was not his
enemy. But he didn't understand that
truth. Let me tell you something.
Dehumanized people dehumanized people.
In order, listen to me y'all. In order
for the devil to have his way in the
human soul, he must first dehumanize.
And when he dehumanizes,
the dehumanized person has no problem
dehumanizing people. And when you
dehumanize people, the people themselves
become your enemy. You no longer realize
that we wrestle against flesh and blood.
So now you see flesh and blood as the
enemy. And the single
the single
most evident
sign
that you are in the image of the beast
is when you see individuals
as the enemy.
Come on, let's go back to the story.
Remember 1st Peter 5:8. The Bible says,
"Your your adversary, the devil, as a
roaring lion walketh about seeking whom
he may devour." This is what God is
trying to warn Cain of Cain. Listen, sin
is crouching at your door. Don't let the
beast in. Don't dehumanize yourself,
Cain. Don't allow yourself to be
dehumanized. But Cain did not listen.
And what he does,
what does he do?
In essence, he says to Abel, "I unfriend
you.
You are the enemy and I unfriend you."
The Bible says in Genesis 4:8, "And Cain
talked with Abel his brother. And it
came to pass when they were in the field
that Cain rose up against Abel his
brother, and slew him. And the Lord said
unto Cain, "Where is Abel thy brother?"
And he said, "I know not. Am I my
brother's keeper?"
Please see how the dehumanization of
Cain led him to be like, "Why should I
care about my brother? Why should I care
about him?"
The evidence that Cain was the seed of
the beast was that Cain was dehumanized.
His brother died and he could have cared
less. his brother died and it didn't
matter to him. You might say, "Who is my
brother?" We'll hold that question for a
moment because you think certainly not
my enemy. My enemy is not my brother for
sure not. But beloved, I'm trying to
tell you something that Satan's plot for
the end of time is to dehumanize the
entire planet.
And the way that he's going to do that
is through wrath.
Cain's countenance fell. He was wroth.
He was angry.
The devil's goal is to turn men from the
image of God into the image of the
beast. And if he can turn you into the
image of the beast through wrath, listen
to me.
In order for you to be dehumanized, he's
got to remove love from your heart. And
once love has been removed from your
heart, wrath takes its place. And when
wrath takes its place, you have been
dehumanized. And dehumanized people
dehumanize
people.
We see this even in the time of Jesus in
chapter in Luke chapter 6. Luke chapter
6 verse 9. The Bible says, "Then said
Jesus unto them, speaking to the
Pharisees, I will ask you one thing. Is
it lawful on the Sabbath days to do good
or to do evil? to save life or to
destroy it. And looking around upon them
all, he said unto the man, "Stretch
forth thine hand." And he did so, and
his hand was restored whole as the
other. And they, watch this, the leaders
were filled with madness. You know what
madness is? It's wrath.
They became beastlike and communed one
with another what they might do to
Jesus. In other words, they wanted to
kill him. Just like Cain,
they were filled with wrath, with
madness. Jesus, we unfriend you. Not
that they were ever his friend. We
unfriend you.
It is interesting. Jesus one time
speaking to the to the Pharisees said
unto them in John 8:43, "Why do you not
understand my speech even because you
cannot hear my word? You are of your
father the devil." Do you remember what
we said earlier about the word of x out
of Jesus is literally saying you
proceeded from your father the devil?
You even though you're a Pharisee even
though you claim to be God's people even
though you claim to be the seed of the
woman you are
a descendant of the serpent in the
garden. You are a descendant of a beast.
You are of your father the devil and the
lust of your father you will do. He was
a murderer from the beginning. Wow. He
was a murderer from the beginning and
abode not in the truth because there is
no truth in him. When he speaketh a lie
he speaketh of his own for he is a liar
and the father of it. So I want you to
understand now that the reason Jesus
said to them you can't understand my
words is because beasts don't understand
words.
Beasts only react off of instinct.
You You can't talk to a dog and say, you
know, you know, dog, um, I was wondering
the other day. I mean, you could say,
"Come and sure, they get that
lie. Okay, they get that." Very simple.
You cannot have a conversation with a
beast.
There's no talking to a beast. A beast
is just not going to hear you. A beast
is just not going to understand. And
notice with me, Psalm 32:9, "Be ye not
as the horse or as the mule which have
no understanding." There's a reason why
God said why Jesus said to them, "You
don't understand my words because you're
of the f you're of your father. Your
father was the serpent. Beasts can't
understand words." In 2 Peter chapter
2:12, but these as natural brute beasts
made to be taken and destroyed speak
evil of things that they understand not.
Jude 1:10, but these speak evil of
things which they knew not. But they
were n but they know naturally as but
what they know naturally as brute
beasts. In those things they corrupt
themselves.
Please understand this concept of the
brute beast
of the beast that cannot hear the
gospel.
God says love your neighbor and you
can't hear that. You can't understand
that. It doesn't compute. You're like
sure I love my neighbor, but who is my
neighbor? My neighbor is represent those
in my camp. My neighbor represents those
who believe like I believe. My neighbor
represents those who like the same
things I like. Surely those are my
neighbors, Lord. You must understand
that. And it's like Jesus is saying, you
are like a beast. You can't understand
when I say love your neighbor. Who is my
neighbor, Lord? Oh, it's those who
believe like I do. It's those that are
on my side.
Notice what 1 John 3:15 says.
Who whosoever hateth his brother is a
murderer.
And you know that no murderer has
eternal life abiding in him. Please
listen to me.
You don't have to murder someone
to murder someone.
And to hate someone
means you've already murdered them.
You may not you may not be able to get a
hold of a long gun rifle and be able to
time on climb on top of a roof and sit
there and wait for your hated target to
come.
But just because you never have the
opportunity doesn't mean the thing isn't
in your heart.
You might say to yourself, "Oh yeah, I'd
never do that." But I need you to
understand, beloved, that the beast
image, the beast heart is deceptive
beyond measure.
And so the devil understands that sure
you may not pull the trigger, you may
not go out and grab the knife, but he
knows if he can at least get you to
hate, you are or you are as good as a
murderer. You are demonstrating the seed
of the serpent. You're you just need to
be wroth. That's all that's all he
requires. That's all he wants. just so
you could be wroth.
Ecclesiastes 3:18, the Bible says, "I
said in my heart concerning the estates
of the son of son sons of men that God
might manifest them, that they might see
that they themselves are beasts." God is
trying to get us to open our eyes to
see, listen, without me, you are a
beast.
If you're not in the image of God, which
image is love, because God is love, then
you are in the image of the beast who
operates instinctly on wrath.
Remember when the disciples were talking
to Jesus and in Luke chapter 9 verse 53
the Bible says this, they did not
receive him because he his face was as
though he was to go to Jerusalem.
talking about this village in which
Jesus uh people rejected Jesus. And when
his disciples James and John saw this,
they said, "Lord, will thou that we
command fire to come down from heaven
and consume them even as Elias did?" But
he turned and rebuked them and said,
"You know not what manner of spirit you
are of?" Wow. You are of
you are operating like beasts right now.
The son of man has not come to destroy
men's life but to save them. Remember
when Peter said to Jesus, you know, far
be from you to go die.
Look what Jesus did. Matthew 16:22.
Matthew 16:23. But he turned and said
unto Peter, "Get thee behind me, Peter."
No, no, no, no, no, no, no. Get thee
behind me, Satan. Thou art an offense to
God. You see, Jesus understood that he
was not wrestling against flesh and
blood. He understood that Peter wasn't
the enemy. He understood that these
people in the village weren't the enemy.
He understood that. But his disciples
struggled with that.
It took them some time to begin to
understand. Wait a minute. Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. We wrestle not against flesh and
blood, but spiritual wickedness in high
places.
In fact, Ellen White says this in Christ
triumph in page 270. He says this,
"Pilate was convinced that no evidence
of the guilt of Christ could be sustain
sub substantiated. Notwithstanding the
priests and rulers had declared that he
had spoken blasphemy. But the Jews were
under the inspiration of Satan as was
Cain and other murderers who have
determined to destroy life rather than
save it."
Quote, "And they were the more fierce,
saying, he stirth up the people,
teaching throughout all jewelry from
Galilee, beginning from Galilee to this
place. Fierceness,
wrath." They were of the same spirit of
Cain.
Please, are y'all understanding what I'm
saying? Thus, I'm building up to
something, y'all. I'm coming down to our
time. So, we've seen what it was at the
beginning. We've seen what it was in the
days of Jesus. And even Jesus prophesied
of the future when he said this these
words. Matthew 24:12, "And because
iniquity shall abound, the love of many
shall wax cold." In other words,
beloved, Jesus said that as time
proceeds, people would get colder and
colder.
The love of many would wax cold.
Almost as if people would begin to
rejoice
over the deaths of their enemies.
rejoice over the death of someone they
don't like. That they would become that
cold that they would actually begin to
rejoice.
You see, understand beloved that if
Satan can dehumanize you with hate, then
you don't have an issue dehumanizing
other people. Dehumanize people
dehumanize people.
And you'll see this plot. That's why I
call it the devil's dehumanization plot
because he's been running it all through
history. In Daniel chapter 7, in Daniel
chapter 7 21, Daniel speaks of this
little horn that made war with the
saints. Daniel 7:21, I beheld and the
same horn made war with the saints and
prevailed against them. And what you
need to understand about this little
horn, beloved, is that this little horn
is on the head of an animal. It's part
of an animal
which signifies that its persecution of
the people of God was because it is of
the seed of the serpent.
We don't have to guess this because the
time period this little horn uh uh uh
persecutes is known as the 1,260
years or the time times and a half. But
when we go to Revelation 12, notice how
Revelation 12:14 puts it.
And to the woman were given two wings of
a great eagle that she might fly into
the wilderness where she has a place
where she's nourished for a time, times,
and a half from the face of the serpent.
Do y'all see this? In Genesis, it was
the woman and the serpent. In
Revelation, it's the woman and the
serpent. In Genesis, it was the seed of
human of of a human seed and a beastly
seed. We find the same thing in
Revelation chapter 12.
This persecuting power is described as a
dragon, a beast,
while the God's people is described by a
woman. H listen to this y'all. Listen to
this.
Speaking of this beast in Revelation
17:5, she's now described, the beast is
now described as a woman. And the Bible
says in verse 5, "And upon her forehead
was a name written, mystery Babylon the
great, the mother of harlots and
abominations of the earth. And I saw the
woman, listen to me now y'all, I saw the
woman drunk with the blood of the saints
and with the blood of the martyrs."
Beloved, that is the wine
of Babylon.
The blood of the saints that she is
drinking. That is the wine of Babylon.
What do you mean, pastor? Listen. The
text says that it is the wine of the
wrath. Revelation 18:3. For all nations
have drunk of the wine of the wrath of
her fornication. This wine is wrath
wine.
Meaning
those who partake of this are
intoxicated with wrath.
And it is that wrath that leads them to
become drunk with the blood of the
saints. This is what was happening
during the dark ages. That's why the
Bible describes this woman as drunk with
the blood of the saints. It is the same
thing. The wine, the wine of the wrath
is symbolic, listen to me, is symbolic
of their hatred with which leads them
like Cain to kill others.
The wine of the wrath, you guys,
is the fact that they're drinking the
blood of the saints. And now remember
this. You don't have to actually drink
the blood of the saints,
the blood of others to drink the blood
of others. Because Jesus said, "If you
hate your brother, you are already
guilty of the wine of the wrath of
Babylon. You are already guilty of the
blood."
Now, I want you to hear this out because
remember
during the dark ages, this church, this
system
was was was getting drunk on this wine,
this wine of wrath. And what I need to
let help you to understand, beloved, is
that wrath is intoxicating and it
intoxicates others.
So while the church in the dark ages
were dehumanizing people because they
themselves were dehumanized,
full of wrath, full of hate,
persecuting in the name of Jesus. They
could look at another individual and
say, "Yes, you deserve to die." And you
deserve to die because and if you can
imagine the the media of that day,
the media of that day must have surely
given every reason why it was good for
that person to die.
Come on y'all. Maybe you don't want to
say amen, but but it's okay. I'll say it
for you. Amen.
They must have given every reason why.
Hey, listen. It's okay not to mourn this
death. It's okay not to really be
empathetic about this death. Because
here is why.
But what I need you to understand that
that kind of wrath that had been being
poured out in Europe over centuries
began to produce another effect. It is
what we call the French Revolution. And
I want to read something to you from the
book Dark Darkness before dawn. It's
also in the great controversy. But
listen to what she says here. We're
going to put it up on the screen. The
teachings of religious leaders have
opened the door to infidelity, to
spiritualism, and to contempt for God's
law. And upon these leaders rest a
fearful responsibility for the iniquity
that exists in the Christian world. Now,
she's talking about post
French Revolution, but the same
principle applies pre-French revolution.
In other words, listen to me now.
What we're being told here is that this
system Babylon churches that reject the
law of God
in their rejecting the law of God, they
are embibing in the wine of Babylon. And
that wine, the law, if the law is
summarized in love and they are
rejecting the law of God, then they're
rejecting the definition of love. And
they are beginning to act while speaking
about love. they can begin to do things
that are the very opposite of love like
burning people at the stake in the name
of Jesus in the name of God. That's what
happened during the dark ages. And that
kind of mentality, that kind of
hypocrisy led to unbelievers in the
French Revolution going, "Hey, we reject
God and we reject the Bible." And the
wrath that had been being poured upon
upon them that they were forced to drink
now gets them drunk on wrath.
Are y'all following what I'm saying?
The primary responsibility
of the condition of the world today is
primarily because the churches have been
teaching that God's law is done away
with. And if God's law is done away
with, then guess what what you're saying
is it's okay to kill.
It's okay to lie.
It's okay to commit adultery. It's okay.
If it's okay to break the Sabbath, then
it must be okay to do all these other
things. That's what the churches have
been teaching to the world. It's okay.
And now the world begins to get drunk
off of this false doctrine, this false
wine, and it produces wrath in them,
which in turn angers Christians even
more. How can you live like this? How
can you do these things? Don't you see?
Listen to this. The same the same master
spirit that urged in the massacre of St.
Bartholomew
led also in the scenes of the French
Revolution. Wow. Wow. Wow. Wow. Listen
to what she goes on to say. The work
which the papacy had begun, atheism
completed. The one withheld from the
people the truths of the Bible. The
other taught them to reject both the
Bible and its author. the seed sown by
priests and pates was yielding its evil
fruit. And she's speaking specifically
about the French Revolution.
If you want to know why America is in a
condition that it is now, it is because
the churches of America have been
teaching for decades that the law of God
is done away with. That the law of God
does not stand. That you are no longer
under the law. You are under grace. that
you don't need to obey the commandments
because Jesus died on the cross and
therefore uh the Sabbath is done away
with as well as every other commandment.
You just kind of gauge for yourself what
is right or what is wrong. And when that
message is coming from the only place in
which sanity should be coming from,
truth should be coming from, then what
do you expect is going to happen to a
nation?
It's not the people's fault that they're
like, "Oh, the law of God doesn't stand
anymore." It's the churches who've been
teaching that
forever.
In this country, forever.
And so what happens, beloved, is that
this wine is is it's almost like a it's
a it's a wine that that it produces more
drunkards.
It produces more drunkards. This man,
and I'm coming to this man, this young
man that killed Charlie Kirk was drunk
on the wine of Babylon.
He was drunk on wrath.
We don't know all the reasons for his
wrath, for his anger, but he was
wrathful enough to become dehumanized
and then dehumanize Charlie Kirk and
then kill him. You can't kill unless you
dehumanize first.
And beloved, here's what we need to
understand as God's people.
Because a lot of us get caught up
get caught up in this cycle of wrath
not realizing where it's all ending,
where it's all headed.
Listen to me y'all. The Bible says in
Proverbs 23:20, "They that tarry long at
the wine, they that go to seek mixed
wine, look not thou upon the wine when
it is red, when it giveth his color in
the cup, when it moveth itself a right.
At the last it biteth like a serpent and
stingeth like an adder. Thine eyes shall
behold strange women and thine heart
shall utter perverse things. May I
suggest to you, beloved, that all who
drink the wine of Babylon will
eventually be brought into the system of
Babylon itself. That's what the Bible
tells us. The whole nation, the whole
world is going to finally unite under
the umbrella of Babylon. And the way the
devil gets them to unite is through
wrath.
When you all have the same spirit of the
beast, you will eventually worship the
image of the beast.
If you are reflecting the image of the
beast. Now when the image of the beast
is actually implemented, you will be
connect. You will be drawn to it. You
will be attached to it. You will be
attracted to it.
This is why the Bible says in Proverbs
chapter 20, wine is a is a marker.
Strong drink is raging. Beloved, this is
why strong drink is raging. When you
begin to rage, when you begin to adopt
the anger,
adopt the wrath
of the world, it is going to lead even
of the professed church. It is going to
lead to something that is not good in
the end. So, Revelation 12:17 says this,
"And the dragon was wroth with the woman
and went to make war with the remnant of
her seed, which keep the commandments of
God and have the testimony of Jesus
Christ." The devil's endgame is to turn
the entire world anger toward the
church. And so many of us in the church
are busy hyping up the anger of the
world. Hyping up the anger of those we
agree with.
And beloved, don't get me wrong. There
are things in the world to be angry
about. But there's a difference between
righteous indignation and false
righteous indignation. And the problem
is that many of us cannot make it out.
Because when godly anger will never lead
you to see people as the beast,
godly anger will never lead you to see
flesh and blood as the enemy. It will
always lead you to understand that we
wrestle not against flesh and blood. I
know those people are doing this, but
they think what they're doing is right.
They think what they're doing is good.
And I get it, but they're not. And
they're deceived. And what can we do to
help those people? It's not, oh, those
people are wicked and let's make let's
let's expose these wicked people. No, we
should expose wickedness, but realize,
beloved, that we are not wrestling
against people. We are not wrestling
against flesh and blood. No matter how
much the devil comes into Peter and
tries to get Jesus to say, "Peter,
you're wicked." Jesus knew Satan, get
thee behind me.
The devil's goal is to get the entire
world drunk on the wine of Babylon.
And watch this. When the Bible says that
the wine of Babylon is given by this
woman, remember a woman represents a
church. So now, now what the text is
telling us is that at the end of time,
the devil will use a counterfeit
righteous indignation
because it's coming from the woman.
She's angry over how the world is not
following God. She's angry over all the
unrighteousness in the world and all the
wicked. Meanwhile, meanwhile, it's the
very same system that is teaching that
the law of God has done away with, that
you don't need to keep the commandments.
It's that very same system that is
attempting to put in place a Christian
nationalistic a theocracy
to solve the problem that lies at her
feet.
And so now Jesus says in John 16:2,
"They shall put you out of the
synagogues. day. The time is coming
where he that kills you will think he is
doing God's service.
The time is coming where he who is angry
with you will think they're being angry
with you in the name of Jesus. Do you
know how many how many of us in the
church are angry with other people in
the church and we think that it is a
holy anger? We think it is holy
righteousness. I unfriend you.
I unfriend you.
Do you know Do you know how many of us
are being trained to see flesh and blood
as the enemy
as we continue to see uh uh um uh videos
put up of people and what this person in
the church does and what this and it's
all designed. Beloved, listen to me.
Social media today is crazy because it's
all designed to channel hate toward an
individual.
The devil knows that hate is a powerful
motivator.
So if he can dehumanize you,
then he can lead you to dehumanize
others.
You see, I was listening to the news uh
um earlier and they were saying that
this the killer of Charlie Kirk said
that Charlie Kirk was full of hate and
spreading hate. Now, I want you to get
catch catch this philosophy.
This 22-year-old man said Charlie Kirk
was full of hate and spreading hate. And
I'm against that. So, what I'm going to
do is do something hateful.
How does that work?
Love has to be moved out of the way in
order for the dehumanized in order for
people to become dehumanized and then
they can de dehumanize other people.
Wrath takes a place of love. The more
the less love you have in your heart for
someone, the more wrath is automatically
placed there.
And so what I want you to understand,
beloved, is that this wine has this
effect where it intoxicates thousands of
people at a time.
There are people
who who were dancing when they heard
Charlie Kirk died.
I want you to think about that for a
moment. People were dancing and
celebrating
saying, "Well, he said not to have
empathy, so I'm not going to have
empathy." But I need you to understand,
beloved, that that whether that
statement is right or wrong, don't have
empathy or or or you know, empathy is a
weakness, whatever,
the fact
that we're at a place in our society now
where people are dancing and celebrating
a death
should scare everybody. But it doesn't
stop there
because you have a whole another group
of people who are saying it is time for
war.
Professed Christian people saying it is
time for war. It is time for revenge,
for vengeance. And I'm I'm what I'm
trying to show you, beloved, is the plot
of the enemy to to get a spirit of to
get the spirit of wrath. wrath. The
spirit of the beast so ingrained in the
human heart,
whether it is openly unrighteous or
disguised under righteousness,
you got to understand how this thing
spreads.
See, see a after this assassination
attempt, a I'm sorry, after this
assassination, this ungodly
assassination,
H.B.CU schools just got sh tons of them.
Virginia State University, my old
school, Oak University, the school I
went to after Adventist school, shut
down because of death threats,
most likely coming from people who claim
to be
Christians, American Christians,
American patriots, people who are like,
"Hey, God, country, what most likely
coming from that because they're angry
about." And you see what happens? The
anger it just keeps it just keeps
spiraling and spiraling and spiraling.
And the more it spirals is the more it
draws people into its cup.
The devil, his goal, his plot is to
dehumanize
and make you think you have the right to
be dehumanized.
This this m the
People are like, "How can you be dancing
at Charlie Kirk?" And now watch this.
There were some Democratic senators,
husband and wife, who were assassinated
a few months back.
And just as now, people are saying,
"Where's the outcry for Charlie Kirk?"
Many of those same people who are
saying, "Where's the outcry?"
Not a word
about that assassination.
And now if you turn on the news, I need
y'all to see what's going on here. But I
need you to put down the cup, please,
and see what's going on.
Because now what's going on is, oh, this
group of people, this political group of
people, they are assassins. They are
murderers. No, no, no. This group of
murderers.
What is time for war?
This country may very well be headed for
a civil war.
And if you know anything about prophecy,
if you've read the writings of the
spirit of prophecy, you will see that
she says a civil war will return to
America.
The devil is seeking to dehumanize
and to have all those who he dehumanize
think they have the right
to be dehumanized.
Beloved, our world is becoming a scary
place. This Ukrainian woman that was
stabbed on the the the train in
Charlotte, I think it's Charlottesville,
and I think to my, you know,
Let me tell you
and let me let me let me
like
I don't understand how an entire
car car full of people saw this and let
that woman just die there.
Let that woman let that man get away.
And I know he got caught in, you know,
eventually.
But
when we get to the place where we become
so desensitized
to am I my brother's keeper? We have
that mentality, that attitude. I need
you to understand that what the devil is
doing, beloved, he is he is dehumanizing
the planet. And many Adventists are
getting caught up in this dehumanization
process. I'm coming to that. Please
listen to me, y'all.
Many of us are getting caught up. You
could just look at the at Facebook
comments and just see the dehumanization
process within our church, within our
members growing stronger and stronger
and stronger.
We rejoice when we hear that those who
don't agree with us, something has
happened to them. Or we just say, "Hey,
my silence is my rejoicing." That's how
we do it.
The Bible says in Proverbs 24:17,
"Rejoice not when thine enemy falleth,
and let not thine heart be glad when he
stumbleth, lest the Lord see it and it
displeas away his wrath from him."
Beloved, we should never be rejoicing.
We should never be rejoicing. That is
the spirit of the enemy.
When George Floyd had a knee put on his
neck
and people were like, "Oh, he deserved
it. Oh, he was a criminal."
Let let me tell you,
the dehumanization process will always
seek to justify why it's okay to
dehumanize an individual.
And we're watching it unfold before our
very eyes.
We're watching this process unfold
before our very eyes where we can see a
death and be like, "He probably deserved
it."
Or we can see a death and be like, "No
need to intervene. No need to stop." Or
we can see a death and rejoice. Listen
y'all,
I want to take these three because
they're an example of what's happening
in the world around us. Charlie Kirk's
death, people dancing.
This Ukrainian woman's death, people
standing by. I'm not doing anything
at least for a time. George Floyd uh he
deserved it. I need you to understand
how the devil is is is fulfilling this
plot. And now you might say, "Well,
well, how is this happening?" uh uh even
in the church or how this happening on
such a large scale. Let me tell you how
it's happening, you guys.
The way that it's happening is this. If
the devil can get you to become
suspicious of flesh and blood, he has
already got you sealed up.
So now what's happening is that we're
getting to a place where where we're
looking at different organizations and
now we're looking at the people in those
organizations saying, "Yeah, those
people are beasts. They are animals."
Let me give you the exhibit, y'all. The
United Nations. Yeah, it's good for us.
It's all right for us to be angry and to
say those people in the United Nations,
they know what they're doing and there's
a plot and there's this and there's that
or the World Economic Forum or the CDC
or the Republicans or the Democrats or
the deep state. We can see these things
and go, "Yo, the the people there are
wicked." And the moment that the devil
can get us to to to
embrace the concept of flesh and blood
as our enemy,
it's the people in the Democratic party.
It's the people in the Republican party.
It's the people in the CDC that trying
to kill us with this vaccine. It's the
people at the United Nations.
It's the people in the LGBT community.
It's the people on the left. It's the
people on the right. It's the people in
BLM. It's the pe once we get to thinking
this way.
And you see, here's what we don't
understand, you guys.
When when when God talks about Babylon,
you understand he's not talking about
the people.
He's talking about the system.
And this is why in Revelation 18:4, the
Bible says, "I heard another voice from
heaven saying, "Come out of her Babylon,
my people, that you be not partakers of
her sin and that you receive not of her
plagues." God knows how to separate
system from people. So, while beloved,
we believe that the papal system is a is
a is an anti-Christian system, we don't
go around saying that the people in the
system are crooked and liars and wicked
and animals and beasts and and whatever
happens to them, they deserve it. We
don't do that.
Even though we believe that that the the
the Christian nationalist movement is a
fulfillment of Bible prophecy.
Revelation 13:11, we don't say the
people in it are wicked. At least we
shouldn't say the people in it are
wicked. They don't know what they're
doing.
Listen y'all. If Jesus himself, if Jesus
knew that Satan was moving in those
Roman soldiers and moving in in in in
the Pharisees and Jesus himself prayed
to the father, saying they don't know
what they're doing.
Now, if anyone ever had the right to
say, "Yep, they are conspiring to do
something that they know is Jesus is the
one that could have been like, "Yep,
it's the people." It's not even Satan.
It's the people. But Jesus himself said
they know not what they do.
How should we be treating people in the
LGBT community?
How should we be treating people
in a party that you may not agree with?
who have embraced racism?
How should we be treating people who
have embraced philosophies we don't
agree with? How should we be treating
people who have embraced doctrines that
we don't agree with? How should we be
treating people?
Jesus says, "Greater love has no man
than this, that a man lay down his life
for his friends."
Who are his friends?
No. Jesus didn't point to someone who
agrees with you. Jesus didn't point to
those who have your philosophy. Jesus
didn't point to those who who act like
you and look like you and and and are
your skin color. Jesus pointed to the
ones that the Jews thought were their
enemies the most. That's your brother.
And so many of us, beloved, in the
church, we have this this smug,
righteous indignation that we can just
tell people they're wicked and tell
people that they support this or that
and thus they are this and that and and
and you're this and and and listen
y'all, it's so infiltrating the church
that we now see that same spirit even
towards our own leadership, even towards
the general ederal conference. We are
now trained. Oh, you're a liberal.
You're a conservative. I hate you. Oh,
you're in the leadership. And we have
this spirit of disdain, this spirit of
wrath,
and we buy into these these these these
uh uh these suspicions.
There is no place that made it more
clearer
than the COVID issue.
Instead of us adopting a spirit of hey,
if you want to be vaccinated, that's
fine. And if you don't want to be
vaccinated, that's fine. No, no, no, no.
It had to be you are the enemy if you
got vaccinated or you are the enemy if
you don't get vaccinated.
It h it couldn't be we wrestle wrestle
not against Russ. No, no, no. It had to
be you bowed your knee to Babylon.
You're preparing to receive the mark of
the beast. It couldn't just be, "Hey,
you were convicted to get it. You were
convicted not to get it. Let every man
be convicted in his own mind." It
couldn't be that. Nope. Nope. Nope.
There was a conspiracy. No, no, no.
There was going to be this was going to
be the beginning of It had to be
something. And beloved, when we have
that disposition that that we have to
find an enemy for a cause, we have to
it's got to be flesh and blood
somewhere. And therefore I unfriend you.
I unfriend you. I unfriend you. Do you
know how much unfriending happened over
CO?
Do you know how many people have
unfriended one another, not realizing
that the devil is planting the spirit,
the very spirit of wrath, and it's only
going deeper and deeper and deeper.
Watch this y'all. Listen to this quote
from the Great Controversy, page 608.
Ellen White says this. As the storm
approaches, a large class who have
professed faith in the third angel's
message, but have not been sanctified
through obedience to the truth abandoned
their position and join the ranks of the
opposition. Now, pause for a second. Who
are the ranks of the opposition?
We know that the ranks of the opposition
represents the papal and apostate
Protestant systems.
What we're being told here in this
statement is that at the end of time
they're going to be Adventists who join
the papacy and apostate Protestantism.
They have become so enamored
with the wrath of these systems. What
are you angry at? What are you angry?
Oh, we're angry at this. Okay, we're ang
and it's a righteous indignation. Here's
what she goes on to say. by uniting with
the world and partaking of its spirit of
its spirit. She calls these systems the
world even though it's a church. She
calls it the spirit of the world because
it is a beastly spirit. She says by
partaking of its spirit, they have come
to view matters in nearly the same
light. In other words, they're on the
same page with everything that's that
apostate Protestantism and and and the
papacy are they believe their
philosophies. They're now on the same
page.
By uniting with the world and partaking
of its spirit, they have come to view
matters in nearly the same light. And
when the test is brought, they are
prepared to choose the easy and popular
side. You know what's going to be the
popular side at this time? It's not
going to be atheism.
It's going to be the image of the beast.
That's where everybody's going to be
flocking to. Men of talent and pleasing
address. Men who were well-known. Men
who could throw out men who who had
podcasts and and all. Men who h
men
of talent and pleasing address who once
rejoice in the truth employ their powers
to deceive and mislead souls. They
become the most bitterest bitter enemies
of their former brethren. When Sabbathke
keepers are brought before the courts to
answer for their faith, these apostates
are the most efficient agents of Satan.
You might be like, "Nah, that that can
never be. That could never be." But
listen, beloved, if you're partaking of
the wrath of Babylon now,
a pseudo wrath
against unrighteousness,
a wrath that points people, that points
to people as the enemy. They are wicked.
They are against us. They have declared
war. This is war. They are the enemy.
Beloved, without understanding Jesus's
distinction that we wrestle not against
flesh and blood, I listen y'all.
The papacy, the issue with the papacy is
its teaching. The people in it are
simply deceived. They're not wicked.
They're not plotting. They're not like,
"Oh man, how can we how can we help the
devil get his plan across?" Beloved, no.
No. That's a very childish approach to
prophecy.
And so what we need to understand,
beloved, is that we must have the spirit
of Jesus who said they know not what
they do.
Jesus was God. If they knew what they
were doing, he would not have said that.
And yet he said, "They know not what
they do." Beloved, we have to come to
that same conclusion. Listen, this
system is wicked. It may be corrupt. It
may be this, that, but they don't know
what they're doing. They think they're
doing the right thing. And I disagree
with them biblically. They're not doing
the right thing, but they don't know
that. I'm giving them the benefit of the
doubt. Why? Because I am my brother's
keeper. That's my brother. People aren't
literally trying to kill you with drugs.
People aren't literally out to Listen,
y'all. People are even when they are
wrong in their position, they're doing
what they think is the best way to go
forward.
And if we don't have that spirit, we're
going to continue to hate one another.
And listen, there's no turning back.
This is a turning point. It is only
going to get worse.
Let me let me say now, it is only going
to get worse. The question is, am I
going to partake of that wine? Listen to
me again, you guys.
There are things to be genuinely angry
about. Righteous indignation. I get
that.
I get that. Unrighteousness.
Yes. Yes. When people are getting
murdered. Yes. Yeah. Racism. Yes. Yes.
You can go down the list of things that
that that deserve righteous indignation.
Senseless murders.
But beloved, how we respond
when we respond with it's vengeance
time. When we respond with I hate you,
when we respond with I hate them, you
are already caught in the enemy's trap.
We're getting ready to close. I want you
to listen to this. I want you to listen
to this.
When Saul dies,
David doesn't rejoice. Listen what David
did. The Bible says, "Then David took
hold of his clothes and rent them, and
likewise all the men that were with him,
and they mourned and wept and fasted
until even for Saul and for Jonathan his
son, and for the people of the Lord, and
for the house of Israel, because they
were fallen by the sword."
I want you to see how David treated
Saul.
When Jesus was on the cross, he prayed,
"Father, forgive them." Luke 23:34,
"Father, forgive them for they know not
what they do." And I want you to listen
to what Ellen White says about this.
Listen what Ellen White says about this.
Then I've got one more verse and we're
going to close up.
She says this. "While the soldiers were
doing their fearful work, Jesus prayed
for his enemies. Father, forgive them
for they know not what they do. His mind
passed from his own suffering to the sin
of his persecutors and the terrible
retribution that would be theirs. No
curses were called down upon the
soldiers who were handling him so
roughly. No vengeance was invoked upon
the priests and rulers who were gloating
over the accomplishment of their
purpose. Christ pied them in their
ignorance and guilt.
He breathed only a plea for their
forgiveness, for they know not what they
do. And now listen to what she says. Had
they known that they were putting to
torture one who had come to save the
sinful race from eternal ruin, they
would have been seized
with remorse and horror. But their
ignorance did not remove their guilt.
For it was their privilege to know and
accept Jesus as their savior. Some of
them would yet see their sin and repent
and be converted. Some by their
impenitence would make it impossible for
the prayer of Christ to be answered for
them. Yet just the same, God's purpose
was reaching its fulfillment. Jesus was
earning the right to become the advocate
of men in the father's presence. And
then this last paragraph, that prayer of
Christ for his enemies embraced the
whole world. It took in every sinner
that has lived or should live from the
beginning of the world to the end of
time. Upon all rest the guilt of
crucifying the son of God. To all
forgiveness is freely offered. Whosoever
will may have the peace with may have
peace with God and inherit eternal life.
Beloved, I want to appeal to you
that you drop the spirit of wrath,
that you drop the spirit of anger, even
the disguise of righteous indignation
against people.
We need to stop demonizing people. God
has not called us to demonize people
because if the people are the demons,
then our targets are going to be people.
And we have not been called to target
people. We've been called to target
systems. We've been called to say
Babylon is fallen is fallen. And when
we're focused on the system, beloved, we
can we can despise the system and yet
love the people.
But the people aren't lovely. That
doesn't matter. But the people are are
acting like beasts. That doesn't matter.
God's call is to is to walk them from
the image of the beast back to the image
of God. It is to show them what Christ
does in the heart to transform the
character. And beloved, as long as we
see each other as the enemy, as long as
we are in the mindset of I unfriend you,
that I unfriend you will ultimately lead
to the point in time where they
It will lead to the point in time where
whosoever does not worship the image of
the beast should be killed and killed in
the name of righteousness. That's where
this is headed.
Lord, help me to put down the wrath
and pick up your love. Help me to live
by that principle that we wrestle not
against flesh and blood. It is not the
people, it is the systems. It is the
systems that get into the minds of the
people and tell the people think this
way, act this way, walk this way. And we
our target is not the people. It is the
system. Lord, teach us to understand
that we wrestle not against flesh and
blood because you know what? The world
is not going to get this lesson.
And the wrath of the world will
eventually be turned upon you and upon
me.
You will be called a criminal.
You will be called a crook.
It will be said of you that your
your death is worthy. Your death has a
noble cause. You should die because you
are not following along.
social media will say of you, "Yeah, he
deserved to die. She deserved to die.
And this is why."
And so, beloved, if you feed into that
spirit now, you're simply feeding the
very spirit that will either swallow you
up and make you one of them, make you
embibe in that same spirit, or the very
spirit that will eventually turn on you.
Why would you feed that spirit?
My appeal today,
I want to read it to you. John 15:12-14.
This is my commandment that you love one
another as I have loved you. Greater
love has no man than this, that a man
lay down his life for his friends. You
are my friends if you do what whatsoever
I command you.
If you were sitting next to Charlie Kirk
and you saw that gun
and you knew that you had the power to
save this man or to have him killed.
If you were on that train
and you saw that man take out that knife
to go attack that
defenseless woman.
If you were there
when George Floyd had that knee on his
neck,
I want you to ask yourself,
what would I have done if I could go
back and change the hands of time? What
would I have done?
Greater love has no man this than a man
laid down his life for his friends.
Jesus said in Matthew 10:22, "You shall
be hated of all nations for my name's
sake, but he that endureth unto the end,
the same shall be saved." Endure in
what? Endure in love.
The love of many is waxing cold. And
it's waxing cold even in the church.
Beloved, it is my prayer.
It is my prayer that we will take our
weapons off of one another. that we will
learn to stop targeting people
inside the church and outside the
church.
That we will deal with the philosophies,
with the systems, deal with those. But
beloved, leave the people alone.
Love the people.
Pray for the people. Be willing to die
for the people.
Love the people.
That is what God has called us to do. If
it's your desire to live by that
principle that we wrestle not against
flesh and blood, but against spiritual
wickedness in high places where you will
stop seeing the people as the enemy.
Stop seeing the pastors, the people, the
leaders, the GC this, the GC that, the
CDC, the the Democrats, the Republicans,
the stop seeing the people as the
problem and focus on what God has called
us to do. He's called us to call out
Babylon and call a people out of
Babylon. If that is your desire to say,
Lord, I'm going to love every soul and
distinguish between the philosophy and
the person. Help me, Lord, that I do not
become dehumanized.
Put that one in the chat. Lord, help me
that I never become dehumanized
and that I will not dehumanize other
people whether I agree with them or not.
If that's your desire, put that one in
the chat
and let us pray that God will make this
a reality in our lives
because beloved, the love of many is
waxing cold. Let's pray. Heavenly
Father, thank you for your love for us.
Thank you that you loved us even while
we were yet your enemies. Lord, with
everything going on in this world around
us, people are calling for vengeance.
People are calling for civil war. And
Lord, if we as a church don't get it
together before these things really
start to go down, we're going to get
swept up in the wrath. And many of us
are already drinking of the wine of this
wrath. Please, Lord,
show us,
show us how to live as you lived. Show
us how to be in your image and not the
image of the beast.
And Lord, please seal the spirit of love
in our hearts that we may know that our
enemy is not flesh and blood, but
spiritual wickedness in high places.
Thank you, Lord. And train us to see
beyond flesh and blood is our prayer in
Jesus name. Amen. And amen. I want to
thank you all for tuning in and we're
going to go ahead and put the link in
the chat for the afterglow. Uh so please
uh we encourage you to to to jump on. We
invite you to join us and we're going to
talk about Sabbath school. We'll talk
about the the uh the uh message today
and you'll get to share your thoughts
and we'll get to fellowship together.
And so again, may God bless you and keep
you and may God keep your eyes focused
on Jesus. In his name we pray. Amen. God
bless you.
Thank you for joining us today. If this
is your first time worshiping with us,
please check out our website at
livingmana.urch.
We are not just here for Sabbath
service. We have weekly programming too
that covers mental health, physical
health, weekly prayer service, financial
health, and proving the existence of
God. It is our desire that our
programming will continue to bless you.
Please continue to pray for us as we
fulfill God's mission to go into all the
world with the gospel of Jesus Christ.
[Music]